[ translation & synchronization: loco-whopper ]
[ 中文翻译、字幕同步：疯狂弥天大幌 ]
《伉伉俪俪》
Einstein was then celebrating...
那时爱因斯坦正庆祝…
...the 70th birthday anniversary...
…他的70周岁诞辰纪念，
...and there was a colloquium
given for him.
在一个为他举办的学术讨论会上，
And he said:
他说：
"God doesn't play dice with the universe."
“上帝不会和宇宙万物玩掷骰子游戏
【指量子力学中的“测不准原理”】。”
No, he just plays hide-and-seek.
是啊，他只玩躲猫猫游戏。
Learn to write screenplays,
television scripts, plays--
学着创作电影剧本、电视剧本、
戏剧、长篇小说、和短篇……
Jesus, they're so full of it.
天哪，真是能扯，你知道。
You can't teach writing.
You expose students...
你根本无法教怎么写作，
那不是教就能教会的，
你知道，你只能让学生去接触…
...to good work and
hope it inspires them.
…好的文学作品，
希望那能给他们以灵感。
Some can write,
others will never learn.
有的人能写那么就写，他们就来上我的课，
而另一些人则永远也学不会。
You lose patience
if the student isn't Dostoyevsky.
要是学生不能成为陀思妥耶夫斯基
或乔伊斯，你就失去了耐心。
No, that isn't true. That's crazy.
不，没这回事，怎么会呢。
It's worth it when you get
a gifted pupil.
当你偶尔会碰上个把很有天赋的学生，
你就会觉得那还是很值的。
A girl in my class
wrote a great story:
我班上就有个年轻的女孩，
她写了一篇奇妙的短篇小说，
"Oral Sex in the Age of Deconstruction."
叫《解构时代的口交》，
- It's full of insight, romantic--
- They're here.
- 极富洞察力和浪漫的……
- 他们来了。
Jack will wanna take us
for Chinese food again.
我保证杰克一定又想
带我们去吃中餐。
I think Sally's tired
of our pasta places.
我想萨莉一定有点受够了
我们吃意大利面的地方。
- Hi.
- Is it supposed to rain?
- 嗨！
- 说今天要下雨吗？
Hi.
嗨！
Let me take your coat.
把外套给我。
I opened some white wine.
You want some?
我开了瓶冰的白葡萄酒。
你想来点儿吗？
They're doing something at 80th.
他们又在弄80号公路，
Jack? You want some cold white wine?
- 他们总是在80号公路上弄个不停。真受够了！
- 杰克？你们想喝点冰白葡萄酒吗？
When I go to your place, it's murder.
你让我去你们那儿，那也够险的。
So, Chinese, right?
I can't talk you into Italian?
那么…是去中国餐馆，对吗？
我说服不了你去吃意大利餐，是吗？
Listen, don't get crazy, you know?
听着，别那么抓狂，你知道？
Before we go out to dinner
we wanna tell you something.
听着，我们出去吃饭之前，
我们想先告诉你们一件事。
- You want to?
- Go ahead.
- 你想来说？
- 不…不，你接着说。
- What? What?
- Somebody tell us.
- 什么事？什么事？
- 总有人来告诉我们吧。
Jack and I are splitting up.
杰克和我准备分手了。
- Oh, I see. It's just--Nothing serious.
- What?
- 噢，我知道，这只是…随便说说的吧。
- 什么？
We discussed this for a long time
and we both think it's for the best.
我们为此已经讨论过很长很长时间了，
我们俩都认为还是这样最好。知道吗？
You are joking, of course.
你们在开玩笑，显然是。一定是个玩笑。
Don't make a big deal, okay?
We're fine.
行行好，别那么大惊小怪的，行吗？
因为我们俩都没事。
- Are you serious?
- We are. We're fine.
- 你们是认真的？
- 我们是认真的。我们没事…我们没事。
- We both-- We discussed it.
- It's mutual.
- 我们俩都…我们讨论过了。
- 这是我们共同的意见。
What do you mean?
你们什么意思啊？
Let's go talk about this at dinner.
嘿，我们…我有个好主意，
我们在饭桌上再谈这事儿吧，
I'm not going out to dinner.
- 现在这样可不是个事儿。
- 我可不想出去吃饭了。
Since when has this been decided?
What are we talking about here?
这都是什么时候决定的事儿啊？
你们这是在胡说些什么呀？她说得对……
We've been discussing it.
这件事我们已经讨论了
很有一段时间了。
Don't be worried.
There's no hostility.
别…别担心了。我们没有变成敌人，
也没有生对方的气。
You see? We're fine.
看见了没有？她…我们很好。
- What is the reason?
- Don't--
- 原因…原因是什么？
- 别把它看成是件悲惨的事。
Gabe, it's none of our business.
- 加布…加布，这不关我们的事。
- 各位，拜托……
Don't turn this into a tragedy.
It's a positive thing.
别把它变成件悲惨的事。行吗？
因为这对我们俩都是十分积极的一步。
How can you break up? It's insane.
你们怎么能就…这么分手了？这简直疯了。
You're Jack and Sally.
You got two kids.
杰克和萨莉，你们是一对。
你们还有两个孩子。
Our kids are grown up.
They're in college.
嘿，我们的孩子已经大了，感谢上帝。
你知道，他们已经在上大学了。
We won't bore you with details.
我们可不想拿细节来烦你们。
I can't get my mind around this.
Since when? You get along so well.
我就是想不明白，从什么时候开始的？
你们俩一直都那么好。
She's right.
Have you met other people?
她说得对。你们认识其他的人啦？
我是说，怎么……
Gabe, it's not our business.
加布…加布，这不关我们的事。
- I'm fascinated by this.
- I feel sick.
- 我只是觉得太奇怪了。
- 我感到很不舒服。
We didn't wanna ruin anything.
嘿，我们并不想毁掉什么东西，明白吗？
- We wanna see what it's like to be--
- Apart for a while.
- 我们只是想看一下…分开了会怎么样，是的。
- 分开一段时间。
Don't not support us.
We've gotten the nerve--
你看，别不支持我们。
我们下了很大的决心才这么做的。
This is insanity.
You'll be back together--
你们绝对是疯了。
你们一星期之内就会重又在一起了。
She's keeping the place in Riverdale.
I'm looking for a place in town.
她打算仍住在我们在里佛岱尔的房子，
我会在城里找个地方。
I just feel shattered.
噢，我感到深受打击。
- Oh, come on, Judy.
- I do.
- 噢，别这样，朱蒂。
- 真的。
Come on, let's eat.
别这样，我们吃饭去，嗯？
What do you mean,
"Come on, let's eat"?
你什么意思？
“别这样，我们吃饭去”？
"Come on"? I can't eat.
“别这样”？我…我吃不下。
- Don't get angry.
- I'm not!
- 别那么生气啊。你生气了。
- 我没生气！我没生气！
- I'm not angry!
- I knew it.
- 我没有……
- 我就知道会这样。
You march in here and announce
you're breaking up?
你们就这样冲进来
宣布你们分手了？
You have two kids!
Why are you doing this?
你…你们有两个孩子！
你们为什么要这么做？
This is not our business.
- 为什么要这么做？
- 这不关我们的事。
Why not? They're our
closest friends!
这怎么不关我们的事啦？
他们是我们最亲密的朋友！
There is no one traumatic event.
嘿，你想知道个简单的答案，
可这并非一朝一夕的事情，这你知道。
People grow apart. It's a lot of
little personal things. Now stop it.
人们慢慢疏离，因为许多个人间的小事
累积而成。所以还是别问了。
I don't wanna hear this bullshit.
我可不想听你这样胡扯，都是扯淡！
- Why is she so upset?
- Judy--
- 她为什么这么心烦？
- 朱蒂，怎么……
She cares about us.
她太关心我们了。
Well, I care about you too.
可我也很关心你们啊。
- Judy!
- We're fine, okay?
- 朱蒂！朱蒂！
- 我们很好，知道吗？
- We wanna do this.
- This is crazy.
- 我们想这样做。
- 这简直疯了。
Why are you taking
this so personally?
朱蒂，你为什么这么把它
当成自己的事情了啊？
I'm upset! All right?
Can't I be upset?
我很心烦！行吗？
我就不能心烦了吗？
I've discussed this in therapy.
朱蒂，你知道，我已经
和我心理医生商量过这事了。
You have? You never said a word!
是吗？你从没透露过一个字啊！
- You said this wasn't our business.
- We were all so close!
- 你自己说过这不关我们的事。
- 是的，可我们的关系那么密切！
I assumed we were.
好吧，是我以为很密切。
She's very upset.
她很心烦，他确实很难过。
Will you please not
turn this into a wake?
嘿，嘿，拜托两位，我们自己
都没觉得什么，你们就别揪着不放了。
Why is this such a personal thing
for you? I don't know what to say.
你看，为什么这么把它当成
你的事情了啊？我不知道说什么好了。
Let's just go out to dinner
and forget it.
我们还是出去吃饭吧，
你知道，忘掉这事。
- Judy, come on!
- I knew this would happen.
- 朱蒂，别这样啊！
- 我就知道这会变成件大事，
“狂飙突进”【骚乱不安】……
So why were you so upset?
那么你为什么会这么心烦呢？
I don't know. I really don't know.
我不知道，我真的不知道。
- It was a total shock?
- Yeah, completely.
- 一点也没想到？
- 是的，完全没料到。
They were so casual about it.
你知道，他们对此太若无其事了。
They didn't seem to be
appropriately upset.
他们看起来一点也没有
那种应该有的不安感。
Were you hurt because Sally never
mentioned anything to you?
你是否是因为萨莉从没跟你
提起过什么，而感觉受到了伤害？
Well....
唔……
I think, if I look hard--
Searching over the time...
我想如果我真的仔细…
你知道，认真回想一下…
...when we were alone together--
…我俩单独在一起的时光，
She may have occasionally
remarked about wondering...
我想她是可能无意间说起过，
你知道，她说想知道…
...what it would be like to be single.
…要是单身一人会怎么样，
Now, with all she knew, all she'd
experienced. That kind of thing.
在她现在了解了很多的事，
经历了很多的事之后。诸如此类的话。
But she never said anything
negative about Jack.
但他从没说过杰克
有什么不好，一点也没有。
Before we go on, tell us
something about yourself.
我们继续之前，对不起，
跟我们介绍一下你自己吧。
So we know who you are.
好让我们对你有所了解。
Okay. My name is Judy Roth.
I'm married to Gabe.
好的。我叫朱蒂・罗斯，
我嫁给了加布。
We've been married about 10 years.
我们结婚已经快10年了。
I work for an art magazine.
We don't have any children.
我在一家艺术杂志社工作。
我们没生孩子。
I have a daughter
from a previous marriage.
但我有个女儿，
是我前一次婚姻生的。
I was married when I was very young,
to an architect.
我很年轻的时候就结了婚，
对不起，嫁给了一个建筑师。
It didn't work out.
It's nobody's fault.
但结果不好，
也不能说是谁的错。
Judy told us they did
finally go to dinner.
朱蒂告诉我们那天晚上
最终她还是一起出去吃饭了。
She said she was tense and nervous,
although the others seemed fine.
她说她很紧张不安，
尽管其他人看起来都还好。
Afterwards, they walked home.
吃完饭后他们从餐馆一起散步回家。
She tried to participate,
but found the atmosphere strained.
尽管她也尽量想参与进去，
但是她发现当时的气氛很凝重。
All in all, she said,
it was a very peculiar evening.
总而言之，她说，
对她来说，这是一个非常奇特的夜晚。
It's amazing, isn't it?
这太有意思了，不是吗？
You think you're friendly
with people and it turns out...
你以为和谁是好朋友，
非常的亲密，可结果却是…
...you really have no idea
what they're thinking.
…你知道，你根本就不知道
他们在想什么。
Do you ever hide things from me?
你有没有什么事瞒着我过？
Me? What kind of things?
我？什…什么样的事？
I don't know. Feelings, you know.
我不知道。感情方面的事，你知道。
Longings. Complaints.
渴望啦，抱怨啦。
No.
没有。
- Do you?
- No.
- 你呢？
- 没有。
Sometimes, maybe.
有的时候吧，也许。
Really? Like what?
真的吗？比如说什么事？
I don't know. You know how
you're always so critical?
我不知道。你知道
你总是对我那么挑剔。
We've had this conversation.
我们以前也讨论过这个。
You're definitely in a strange
mood tonight.
你看，你今天晚上的情绪
绝对很奇怪。
I'm fine. I'm sorry.
我没事。对不起。
Jack never gave you an inkling?
It's strange, you guys are so close.
那么杰克从没给你过什么暗示吗？嗯？
这太奇怪了，你们俩关系那么密切。
I remember one incident
he mentioned at his office.
实际上我是记得他跟我提起过
在他办公室发生的一件事。
Jack, trust me on this.
杰克，你一定要相信我跟你说的这事。
This girl is to die.
你会愿意为这女孩去死。
Shawn Grainger, she's built
out to here.
她名叫肖恩・格林杰，
天生就是干这行的。
You will have the time of your life.
你会觉得这辈子都没这么快活过。
And for $200, believe me,
it's a bargain.
要200块钱，相信我，那绝对值得。
I'm not gonna do it.
What about AIDS?
嘿，我可不想和鸡上床。
染上艾滋病怎么办？
She's not a whore.
She's a high-class call girl.
她又不是街上的野鸡，
她是个高级应召女郎。
She'll do anything you want.
And on top of it, she's got friends.
她会做任何事，只要你需要。
除此之外，她还有其他姐妹。
What about my wife?
It's dangerous.
我可不会对我妻子做这样的事，
明白吗？这太危险了。
Who was the guy who told me...
你看，是谁跟我抱怨…
...that your sex life
wasn't so terrific?
…说你的性生活不那么满意的？
Come on, at a two-martini
lunch I'll say anything.
噢，得了吧，午餐桌上多喝了两杯
马提尼，我什么都会胡说。
Shawn has got a mouth
like velvet. Believe me.
肖恩的嘴巴就像是天鹅绒，
我不骗你，真的像天鹅……
She was a former
Miss Something-or-Other.
她以前好像得过
什么什么小姐的称号。她得过……
What exactly did I say at lunch?
你听着，我午饭时到底说了些什么？
You said that Sally was cold,
and you were...
你说萨莉很冷，你很想…
...dying to fuck your aerobics trainer.
你很想和你的有氧健身教练干一把。
I should never drink at lunch.
我绝对不该在午餐时喝酒。
I'm gonna write down the number.
你看，这么着吧，
我把她的电话号码写给你。
- I advise you to--
- What are you doing?
- 我建议你…我建议你……
- 你这是干什么？
Hey. What--?
嘿，怎么……？
Have I steered you wrong?
- 我没给你指错过道吧？
- 你还是走吧。
- I've never--
- Get out of here.
- 我从没给你指错过道。
- 快出去！
There it is. Use it.
好吧。这个给你，好好利用。
He called. I thought it was about
a month after he got my number.
他打电话给我。我记得那大概是
他拿到我电话号码一个月以后的事了。
He was polite on the phone.
A little tense.
在电话里他很有礼貌，
有点儿紧张。
I can always tell who's inexperienced.
你知道，我总能够分辨出
一个人有没有这方面的经历。
He wanted to meet
at the Americana Hotel.
他约我在“大美洲饭店”见面。
When I got there he was very polite,
very gentlemanly. Very nervous.
当我到那儿之后，他非常客气，
彬彬有礼，也非常紧张。
He couldn't go through with it.
He couldn't get it up.
但是他没能完成性行为，
因为他挺不起来。
He had pains in his chest.
当我们在那儿时，
他感觉他胸口特别的疼，
I thought it was a heart attack,
but they passed.
我以为他心脏病发作了，
不过后来就好了。
- That was the last you saw of him?
- He called a couple of months later.
- 那是你最后一次见他吗？
- 不，一两个月后他又给我打电话。
We met at the same hotel.
This time he slept with me.
我和他在同一家饭店见面。
这一次，他和我上床了。
Then I started seeing him fairly
regularly, every two, three weeks.
之后，我开始比较有规律地与他交往，
两到三个星期见一次。
He said he'd seen a psychiatrist
and worked out his problem.
他说他一直在看心理医生，
想解决他的问题。
Once I couldn't make it
so I sent a friend.
有一次我去不了，
我就喊了我的一个朋友代我去。
Then he started seeing both of us.
之后他就开始约我们两个人，
你知道，轮流着来。
Then neither one of us
ever saw him again.
呃…再后来我们两个就
再也没见到他了。
At least he threw the number away.
这么说他再也没打电话给她，
至少他良心发现把那号码丢了。
Well, as far as I know.
嗯，据我所知是这样。
But Jack is not a hooker guy.
不过，你知道，杰克不是那种
喜欢和妓女鬼混的人。
He's very strait-laced.
杰克还是挺一本正经的。
And Sally's cold in bed.
萨莉在床上很冷？
That's no surprise.
She's very cerebral.
我倒不觉得这有什么奇怪的，
反正她是属于那种十分理智型的。
Am I cold in bed?
我在床上冷吗？
No. Why would you say that?
没有。为什么这么问？当然不是。
But I'm inhibited, right?
You said that.
不是吗？可是我放不开，对吗？
我记得你自己这样说过。
You can't forget that.
We had one minor argument years ago.
太好玩了。你老忘不掉这事。
几年前，我们为此发生了一次小的争执，
Which you blew up into
a major confrontation--
可你却小题大作，到最后变成了大吵大闹，
所以你就忘不掉了。
Do you ever want to sleep
with a whore?
你有没有过
想和个妓女上床的冲动？
Me? No, definitely not.
- 我？没有，绝对没有。
- 没有吗？
When I was in college, I did.
有过，是的，当我念大学的时候，有过。
Yeah?
是吗？
You're in an odd mood. Their breakup
has definitely affected you.
你今晚的情绪很怪，我可以看出来。
我想杰克和萨莉的分手绝对影响到了你。
You think--
你认为……
You think we'd ever break up?
你认为我们以后可能分手吗？
What? I'm not planning it, are you?
这算什么问题？你知道，
我可没做这样的打算。你呢？
- No.
- Okay.
- 没有。
- 那就好。
But I don't know how I'll feel if you
still don't wanna make me pregnant.
可是我不知道这会让我有什么样的感觉，
要是你继续不想让我怀孕的话。
Are we gonna have that
conversation again?
嘿，我们又要重复一遍
这样的对话了吗？
- You have a daughter--
- Yeah.
- 你看，你已经有了一个女儿。为……
- 是的。
I want another.
- 我还想要一个，我还想再要一个。
- 她是个很不错的女孩。
Why?
为什么？为什么这这么重要？
It's cruel to bring life
into this terrible world.
带新生命来这个可怕的世界
是很残酷的事，你知道。这不是……
Don't glorify your refusal
on philosophical grounds.
得了吧，别找哲学理由
来美化你的拒绝了。
You should see the angry look
on your face when you say that.
这叫什么话。你应该看看
你说这话时你脸上的气愤表情。
You wanna make love?
你想做爱吗？
Okay, if we can get
into it in some way.
好的。可是…你知道，
如果我们能调整好情绪的话。
- I can't just do it on command.
- We can get into it.
- 我不能就这样像接受命令似的去做。
- 我们能调整好情绪。
Okay, so put your diaphragm on.
- 好吧，把子宫帽戴上。
- 好的。
You'd never say you were
putting your diaphragm on...
嘿，你…你不会跟我说
你去戴上子宫帽…
...and then not do it, right?
…然后却又不想做了，对吗？
What?
什么？
What a thing to say!
你怎么能这么说！
That's a terrible thing to say.
你这样说真是太可怕了，我的天哪！
You really trust no one. No wonder
people accuse you of cynicism.
你真的是谁都不相信，是吗？
怪不得大家都说你玩世不恭。
- Okay. I apologize.
- Jesus!
- 好吧。对不起，我道歉。
- 天哪！
- I'm tired. It's 1 a.m.
- We don't have to do it.
- 我有点累了，已经凌晨1点了。
- 我们又不是非做不可。
- Are you still attracted to me?
- Yes, I am.
- 我对你还有吸引力吗？
- 是的，你对我还有吸引力，你知道。
- Truly?
- Of course.
- 真的吗？
- 是的，你很吸引我，当然。
- We do it less and less.
- Our schedules are not exactly--
- 可是我们做得越来越少了，你知道。
- 你看，只是我们的作息时间不太相配。
When we wanted to, we found time.
这是鬼话，你知道，要是想做，
我们总可以找到时间的。
- Come here.
- Parties, people's bathrooms--
- 嘿，过来，到这边来。
- 在人家的晚会上、在人家的卫生间里…
Sit and relax for a minute, will you?
- 不管在哪里。
- 你坐下来放松一下，行吗？
If you remember clearly, when we
used to do that spontaneous sex...
如果你回忆清楚的话，你该记得
以前我们即兴做爱的时候，
...you never really liked it.
You were always tense.
你很…你知道，你从没真正喜欢过。
你总是很紧张，
You always heard people
in the next room making noises.
你总是听见人们在隔壁房间里吃东西，
或在餐厅里弄出动静。
Now you remember it
in a glorified way.
还记得吗？你现在想起来
却觉得那是种美事？
- Are you ever attracted to other women?
- Like who?
- 你有没有被其他女人吸引过呢？
- 谁啊？比如说谁啊？
Like all the women you have in class,
who are so talented and insightful.
唔，比如说你班上的那些女生，
她们都很有才华、很有见地。
I'm sure they worship you.
你知道，我肯定她们都很崇拜你。
Can I tell you that they don't
want an old man? All right?
我可以告诉你她们不会
想要找个老男人的，明白吗？
I think an old man does better
than an old woman.
我想老男人比老女人有优势。
Then we're definitely
stuck with one another.
好吧，那我们干脆互相不离不弃好了。
Now, come on. You're really....
好了，别这样。你真的……
Come on.
别这样。
Some time later,
Sally had a date with Paul...
几星期后，萨莉
有个晚餐约会和保罗，
...a colleague at work
who had always liked her.
她工作上的同事，
他一直很喜欢她。
- Sally. Come in.
- Thank you very much.
- 你好，萨莉。请进。
- 你好。非常感谢。
Come into my rent-stabilized den.
快到我的受《房租稳定法》保护的小窝里来。
- Can I take your coat?
- It's lovely.
- 把外套给我好吗？
- 这地方很可爱。
I love it. Thank you.
我很喜欢。谢谢。
I thought we'd have a drink.
我想就…我想我们喝点什么。
I was able to get tickets
to Don Giovanni.
我弄到两张《唐・乔瓦尼》
【又名《唐・璜》，莫扎特歌剧】的票。
- Great.
- You all right?
- 很好。太好了。
- 你没事吧？
Yes, yes. I...
没事，没事。我……
- What would you like?
- Anything. White wine?
- 你想要喝什么？
- 什么都行。唔…白葡萄酒？
White wine.
白葡萄酒。
I hear the staging of this opera
is not to be believed.
我听说这次上演的这出歌剧
好得令人难以相信。
Oh, really? How fabulous.
哦，是吗？太棒了！
That's lovely.
好极了。
Oh, hey, don't worry about it.
I'll get it later.
噢，嘿，别担心，别担心。
我过后再收拾吧。
- Can I use the phone?
- Yeah, sure. You all right?
- 我能用一下电话吗？
- 可以，当然。你没事吧？
- I'm looking forward to it.
- This way.
- 没事，没事。我一直期待着这次相约。
- 这边来。
A good friend of mine did the sets.
我的一个好朋友做的布景。
It's me. You are living with her,
aren't you? You've moved in together.
是我。你和她住在一起了，是吗？
你们搬在一起住了。
Don't lie to me, Jack. You are.
别对我撒谎了，杰克。
你现在和什么人住在一起了。
Because I know.
因为我知道。
Because I do.
因为我就知道。
Yes, I heard.
是的，我听说的。
It's been three fucking weeks!
别跟我胡扯了，
这他妈的才三个星期！
How did you meet someone so fast?
你怎么可能这么快就认识别的人？
Bullshit. You had to have
known her before.
噢，胡扯。你肯定以前就认识她。
Bullshit! Don't give me that shit!
扯淡！别跟我鬼扯了！
Oh, you're in love?
噢，你们爱上了？
So fast?
那么快？
I don't fucking believe it!
我他妈的简直不敢相信！
You were seeing whoever it is
all along.
不管她是谁，你都是
一直在保持和她来往。
Of course, I expected things
to happen. But not so fast!
我当然知道会有新的状况出现，
但也不能这么快吧！
Are you that sure?
你那么肯定？
No, I'm not.
不，我没有。
Oh, God, it's just fucking
dishonest bullshit!
噢，天哪，都是他妈的骗人的鬼话！
Hi, you--?
嗨，你…呃…你……？
I'm fine.
我没事。我没事。
- If you're having a personal--
- Really. I'm okay.
- 听着，如果你有什么私事……
- 真的，我很好。
I'm looking forward to tonight.
What are we seeing?
我一直期待着今晚。
我们去看什么？
Don Giovanni.
呃…《唐・乔瓦尼》。
A Don Juan story.
唐・璜的故事。
I can only think of it as Mozart.
我只知道是莫扎特的作品。
Fucking Don Juans.
去他妈的唐・璜。
They should have cut his
fucking dick off.
他们应该把他妈的
他的鸡巴割下来。呵呵……
Can I get you some more wine?
呃…要我再给你倒一点酒吗？
Please.
好的。
You know, we don't have to go.
你看，我们…我们不一定非得去。
No. I'm not gonna
put my life on hold.
不。不…不，我可不想
让我的生活停滞不前。
I've been dying to see this opera.
我一直非常想去看这出歌剧。
- Excuse me one second.
- Sure.
- 原谅我失陪一下。
- 当然。
Hello. Me again.
喂，还是我。
I know who she is.
我知道她是谁。
Bullshit! It's Gail.
胡扯！她是盖尔。
She's been after you since she joined
the firm. You both like sports!
当然就是盖尔。自从她加入你们公司
她就追着你不放。你们俩都喜欢什么狗屁运动！
Don't lie to me, Jack.
别对我撒谎了，杰克，
当然就是盖尔。
She's your type.
She's got that look.
她就是你所喜欢的那种类型，
她看上去皮肤黝黑。
She's bright and all that
Princeton bullshit! No!
她…她聪明伶俐，还是他妈的
普林斯顿的什么玩意儿！不！
I thought it was an experiment!
I didn't think it was final.
不！不！我…我以为这…这只是个试验！
我没有想到这是最终的结果。
I didn't realize you were
having an affair!
我没有料到你居然会有婚外情！
That's bullshit! I don't
buy a fucking word of it!
是吗？真会胡扯！
我他妈的一个字都不会相信！
- What time do we have to be there?
- Listen...
- 什么时候我们必须赶到那儿？
- 听着，我……
...I don't really think I can
do this. I'm feeling upset.
…我想我真的做不了这事，
我感觉很心慌。
What are you upset about?
Fucking men!
你心慌个什么劲？
去他妈的男人！
A woman gets to this age,
it's a different ball game.
女人一跨过某个年龄，
情势就完全不一样了。
Don't defend your sex! It's true!
- 不…不是……
- 别为你们的性别辩护！这是事实！
It's great till you start to show your
age, then they want a newer model.
你人老珠黄之前一切都很好，
可之后他们就想要有新的目标了。
Sally.
萨莉，萨莉！
Sally, you're--
萨莉，你是个……
You're a very attractive woman,
for any age.
你是个很有魅力的女人，
不管你年龄多大。
It was a terrible blow to my ego.
I thought he loved me.
这对我的自尊心是个可怕的打击，你知道。
我以为他爱我，我以为…
That we were experimenting.
…我们只是试验一下，你知道。
But if you had met someone first...?
可是假如是你先认识了
别的什么人，会怎么样？
Probably right.
也许你说得没错，
Probably would've done the same thing.
也许我也会像他这么做。
I had fantasized about
being single many times.
有许多次，我幻想过
重又单身一人，你知道。
It's hard to keep a marriage
going smoothly.
要保持一桩婚姻不起波澜
是很艰难的事，你知道。
All the frustration and baggage.
I don't know.
所有的挫折和负担，
我不知道。
I don't know.
Gail came to his office
the year before.
盖尔一年前来到他办公室。
I'd met her several times.
我和她见过几次面。
Look, what can I say? She's...
你看，让我怎么说呢？她很…她很…
...cultivated, intelligent.
…有涵养，也很聪明。
It's what he likes.
都是他喜欢的。
She'd been over to the house
a few times.
她还来过我们家里几次。
She loved my taste in everything.
She even dressed like me.
她很欣赏我各方面的品味，
她甚至连着装打扮都有点像我。
What can I say?
She's me, but she's younger.
我能说什么呢？
她就是我，但她年轻得多，你知道。
Listen, your short story
was absolutely fabulous.
嘿，听着，你的…你的那个
短篇小说写得绝对很妙。
- Really?
- Yeah.
- 真的吗？
- 是的，真的。
I was very impressed, I must say.
给我印象非常非常深，我得承认。
It was probably the best this term.
我认为它也许是这个学期
我读到过的最好的东西了。
- It was wonderful.
- That's great!
- 真的非常棒。
- 噢，太好了！
The insights were great,
the prose was very graceful.
见解非常的深刻，
行文也很优美。
You know, in general, I was impressed.
你知道，总体来说，给我印象深刻。
- God, I'm blushing, right?
- Well, don't--
- 噢，天哪，我脸红了，是吗？
- 不，别啊，你知道……
My face gets all red.
我一定满脸通红。
I may just cry.
我都要哭了。
Well, don't take it that badly.
I meant it as a compliment.
可别当成是坏事情啊，
我这是夸奖的意思。
It was great. Wonderful.
- 没有。我知道。
- 真的很棒，见解很妙。
Your approbation means
more than anybody's.
你的认可比任何其他人的
都更有意义。
You're the reason why
I wanted to write.
我是说，你就是当初
我想开始写作的原因。
- Really?
- Yeah.
- 是吗？
- 是的。
My family and I, we used to quote
"The Grey Hat."
我家里人和我，我们经常引用
《灰色的帽子》里的句子。
How do you remember that story?
噢，天哪，你们怎么记得那篇小说的？
"Giving up his hopes...
“放弃他的希望，
"...compromising one's dreams,
is like putting on a grey hat."
“不再继续梦想，就像是
戴上了一顶灰色的帽子。”
I love that!
我超喜欢！
You remember that. That's great.
你还记得，那太好了。
Listen. You can hear my heart beating.
你看，你可以听到我的心跳了。
How'd you get the name Rain?
你的名字“莱恩”【雨】是怎么得来的？
My parents named me after...
我父母按照【莱纳・玛丽亚・】里尔克给我…
...Rilke.
…取的名字。
- Did they?
- Yeah, it's my mother's favorite poet.
- 是吗？
- 是的，他是我妈妈最喜欢的诗人。
So that's how I got it.
所以我就有了这个名字。
Are your folks, you know, writers?
你家里人也是，你知道，作家还是……？
No, my dad's an investment banker
and my mom works at Lincoln Center.
噢，不，我爸爸是投资银行家，
我妈妈在“林肯中心”工作。
Are you an only child?
你是唯一的孩子？
- Why are you asking these questions?
- I'm interested.
- 你为什么要问这些问题？
- 噢，我只是…只是很感兴趣。
I was so impressed.
我…我…你知道，
我对那篇小说印象太深了，
I gave it to someone else
and she was also impressed.
我也把它给别的人读了一下，
也给她留下了十分深刻的印象。所以我……
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
- Are you from New York?
- I'm from East End Avenue.
- 是的，你知道。你家在纽约吗？
- 噢，是的，我们住在“东区大街”。
- Are these too many questions?
- No.
- 我是不是问了太多的问题？
- 不，没事。
It's just the only child one.
Yes, I was an only child. Yeah.
是只有一个孩子，
是的，我是唯一的孩子。是的。
So how did you manage
to write something so deep?
那么你是怎么…怎么能够写出
如此…如此深刻的东西的？
I mean, have you had a--?
我是说，你有没有……？
Have you been married and divorced?
你有没有结过婚和离过婚？
Is your whole family stormy
and tempestuous or--?
你的家庭是不是充满了
喧嚣和狂躁，或……？
What? I didn't know I was stormy
and tempestuous.
什么？我不认为我很喧嚣和狂躁。
Well, the writing was very--
唔，你的文笔很…你知道……
- It was intense.
- I don't know.
- 很有力度。
- 我不知道。是啊……
It's just a trick, you know?
It's like...
这…这只是个花招，你知道？
大概…呃…
...when I was 10, I wrote
this story on Paris...
…我在10岁的时候，
我写了一大篇和巴黎有关的故事，
...and I'd never been there.
可是我甚至从没去过那儿，你知道。
You don't have to--
It's just a trick.
你不是非得……
这只是个花招。
- You don't have to know or--
- Can you just turn it out?
- 你不必认识或者…是的。
- 你可以随便就编个出来？我是说……
There are a number of very good
professors who are notorious...
有一些非常非常好的教授，
他们因为勾引…
...for seducing their female pupils.
This goes on...
…他们的女学生而声名狼藉。
这样的事一直不断，
...because it's a cinch.
因为这太易如反掌了。
You know, they look up to them.
你知道，她们仰慕他们，
You know, they're older men...
你知道，他们都一把年纪，
...and students are flattered
by the attention.
学生会因为受到了关注而沾沾自喜。
It's not something I've ever done.
Not to say I haven't had daydreams.
我从来没做过这样的事情。
倒不是说我没有在课堂上做过白日梦，
Some of those women are
very attractive and interesting.
她们中的一些确实
很有魅力也很有意思。
But I've never--
可我从来没有……
I've never acted on it.
我从来没有付诸过行动。
I've never cheated on Judy.
你知道，我从没欺骗过朱蒂，
Or any other relationship
in my life, really.
或我一生中任何其他的关系，真的。
Because that has not been my style.
因为那不是我的风格。
But, once--
但曾有一次，很多年以前…
One time, many years ago...
有一次，很多年以前了，
...I was living with this fabulous,
interesting woman...
那时我和这位十分奇妙的、
很有意思的女人住在一起，
...named Harriet Harmon.
她名叫哈丽特・哈门。
I'm ashamed to say this,
but Harriet Harmon...
我不好意思这样说，
但哈丽特・哈门仍然是…
...was the great love of my life.
…曾经是我生活中最爱的人。
It was a very passionate relationship.
I loved her very intensely.
那是一种充满着激情的关系，
你知道，我非常非常强烈地爱着她。
And, you know, we just
made love everywhere.
你知道，她…我们会在各种地方做爱。
She was sexually carnivorous.
她…她对性简直贪得无厌，你知道。
We did it in stalled elevators...
她…她…我们在卡住了的电梯里做，
...and in bushes and people's houses,
at parties in the bathroom.
在灌木从里、在人家的屋子里、
在晚会的洗手间里做。
In the back of cars, she'd
put a coat on our laps...
我不想告诉你，在汽车的后座上，
她会用一件外套盖住她双腿，
...and grab my hand and
stick it between her legs.
一把抓过我的手
就往她的两腿之间塞。
She was really something.
她真的非常…与众不同。
And she, you know,
she was highly libidinous.
她…你知道，她…她…呃…
非常…非常…利比多过剩。
You know? She wanted
to make love with other women.
明白我意思吗？她以前常常…
她想与其他的女人做爱。
She got into dope for a while.
She'd break that thing...
她以前…她有一阵子迷上了毒品，
她会打开那玩意儿，
...that you sniff when she'd
have her orgasm.
吸上一口，然后她就会有高潮。
I was getting a real education.
你知道，对我来说，真让我大开眼界。
I was fascinated.
I was absolutely nuts about her.
我被她…你知道，被她弄得神魂颠倒，
我完全为她而疯狂。
And ultimately she wound up
in an institution.
可最终，你知道，
她被送入了精神病院。
I mean, it's not funny,
it was a very sad thing.
我是说，这并不好玩，
这是件很悲哀的事。
She was great, but nuts.
她很棒，你知道，但很疯狂。
See, I've always had this penchant...
你瞧，我一直有这样的嗜好，
...for what I call "kamikaze women."
喜欢那种我称之为“神风女子”的女人。
I call them kamikazes because
they crash their plane.
因为她们…我称她们“神风”因为，
你知道，他们撞毁飞机，自我毁灭，
They crash it into you,
and you die with them.
但他们是冲着你撞过来，
于是你就和他们同归于尽了。
As soon as there's little chance
of it working out...
只要存在挑战，只要成功的机会微乎其微，
或干脆没有机会，只要存在困难或障碍，
...something clicks in my mind.
Maybe because I'm a writer.
我心里就会产生一种莫名的兴奋，
也许那是由于我是个作家。
A dramatic or aesthetic component
becomes right...
可是如果某种戏剧性的
或审美的要素恰到好处，
...and I go after that person.
我就会追逐那个人。
There's a certain dramatic ambience
that's almost...
这样就会形成某种戏剧性的氛围，
仿佛我…
...as if I fall in love
with the situation.
…或多或少地爱上了那个人，
爱上了那种状况。
Of course, it has not
worked out well for me.
当然，那种状况的结局
对我来说并不太好，
It has not been great and--
结果不算很好……
A few weeks after Jack
and Sally split--
言归正传，杰克和萨莉
分手几个星期之后……
You know, he and I didn't speak much.
你知道，他和我交谈得不多，
I found him elusive.
We spent more time with Sally.
因为我发现那段时间他在躲着我们。
我们花更多的时间陪着萨莉。
She was depressed.
We'd try and cheer her up.
她很沮丧，你知道。
我们一直想方设法让她高兴起来。
I'd be scared to live alone
where you live.
要是让我独自一人住在你住的地方，
我一定很害怕。
It's really scary.
是很害怕，真的很吓人。
There have been burglaries.
My neighbor was robbed.
那里发生了一系列的入室盗窃。
我邻居的房子就被抢过。
And nearby, people were at home.
还有附近一家，人都在家里。
It's lucky for them
they didn't wake up.
我是说，算他们走运，
他们没醒过来。
I would die. I'd never
close my eyes at night.
我一定吓死了，在夜里
我一定再也不敢闭上眼睛。
- You wanna get something to eat?
- Sure.
- 那么怎么说？你们想吃点什么或……？
- 好的。
Hey.
嘿！
- This is Sam.
- Hi.
- 这是萨姆。
- 嗨。
- This is Gabe and Sally.
- This is Judy.
- 这是加布，这是萨莉。
- 这是朱蒂。
- I have to go. Sorry.
- Don't be silly.
- 唔…你们看，我得走了，对不起了。
- 噢，不，你别傻了。
No, I have an appointment.
不，不，我有个约会，真的。
- Really?
- Don't be crazy.
- 真的吗？
- 你别…你别发疯了。
- I have to go.
- We were gonna eat.
- 不，我是有个约会，我必须得走了。
- 我们正想弄点东西吃。
I just wanted you--
我只是想…你们……
God!
噢…天哪！
- Some coincidence.
- I know.
- 真是巧，哈？
- 是的。
- What was your name?
- Sam.
- 呃…我刚才没记住你名字？
- 萨姆。
Sam. Right.
萨姆，对了。好的，萨姆。
- So you guys are just walking?
- We just had lunch.
- 那么…那么你们俩只是在这儿转转还是……？
- 是的，我们才在街对面吃完午饭。
- What do you do, Sam?
- Aerobics.
- 你是做什么的，呃…萨姆？
- 有氧健身。
And I'm a trainer and some nutrition.
我是…我是教练，
兼做点营养师的工作。
You wanna have dinner at the house?
嘿，你们俩晚些时候有什么打算？
你们想去家里一起吃晚饭吗？
- She's a great cook.
- I am.
- 她的厨艺好得你们不敢相信。
- 噢，我是的。
I don't think--
我想…我想今晚我们去不了。
- It's vegetarian.
- We can't.
- 我们全吃素菜。
- 我们不行…今晚我们不行。
- You don't eat meat, do you?
- I don't. She eats a little.
- 等等，你们不喜欢吃肉，是吗？
- 是的，我不喜欢。她吃一点儿，可我不……
- 有时吃点。
I used to eat meat, then I gave it up.
Then I had some again...
我以前每天都吃牛肉，然后我就戒了。
可我最近又开始吃一些了，
-...and I got so bloated!
-Or there's a Mexican place.
- 所以我一下子就胖得不得！真太糟了！
- 如果不想做，我们可以叫外卖，
拐角处有一家小墨西哥餐馆。
- Oh, yeah! I flip over couscous!
- You feel like cooking?
- 噢，是的！我狂爱吃“库斯库斯”
【蒸粗麦粉，是北非食物而非墨西哥食物】！
- 你还是喜欢自己做？
- Whatever you want.
- Let's do it.
- 你想怎么样就怎么样吧。
- 就这么定了，就这么定了！快点！
Yeah. We'll watch the Grammys.
- 是的，我们可以呆在屋子里，看“格莱美”。
- 我去不了，我去不了，因为……
I'm not watching that.
我可不想看“格莱美”。
她就喜欢看那些傻不啦叽的节目。
- I bet Jill over the best single!
- I'm not watching the Grammys.
- 我指望吉尔赢得最佳单曲呢！
- 我不想看“格莱美”！你为什么非要看呢？
- My mother's in town.
- Yeah, she's here for a week.
- 我妈妈来城里了，所以我去不了。
- 是的，他妈妈要来城里，呆完整个周末。
Okay, maybe later.
I've been meaning to call.
好吧，那就以后找个机会吧。
我一直想给你打电话来着，你知道……
I'd like to pick up some decaf.
既然已经到了这儿，
我想去买点无咖啡因的咖啡。
Oh, there's a great store.
I need some ginseng.
噢，是的，那边有家很棒的商店，
我需要买些人参。
She is so great. You know,
she's got a degree in psychology.
她真的很特别，她真的特别棒。
你知道，她获得过心理学学位。
- She's into fitness.
- You're fucking nuts.
- 她真的非常喜欢她的…她的健身运动。
- 是啊，你真他妈疯了。
She is terrific. She's a nice girl.
Her family's from Delaware.
嘿，她棒极了，她很投入她的健身。
她是个很不错的女孩，她家在特拉华，
Her father's in police work.
她父亲…她父亲在警察局工作。
I can't get my mind around it.
You leave Sally for this? I'm shocked.
我就是想不明白，
你离开萨莉就是为了她？我很震惊。
- Careful. I'm serious about her.
- You're my friend, I love you.
- 嘿，小心点，伙计。我对她是认真的。
- 我知道。可你看，你是我朋友，我爱你。
It's like your IQ is in remission.
我是说，你怎么…我们是这么多年的朋友了，
你的智商好像突然间就衰退了，
- It's like you had a stroke.
- Don't give some moralizing discourse.
- 你知道，好像你得了中风、好多次中风还是怎么着。
- 噢，拜托，拜托！别给我上什么道德课。
- You're not my rabbi.
- I just can't believe it.
- 你又不是我的拉比，你还是闭嘴吧。
- 我只是觉得…只是觉得难以置信。
You're with Sally for years.
You raise a family. She's wonderful.
你和那个女人结婚已经这么多年了，
你们养育了孩子，你知道，她很出色。
- So she's a ball-breaker sometimes--
- She is.
- 好吧，她有的时候是会让人蛋疼……
- 她让我“蛋疼”……
I lived with her, you don't know her.
嘿，不用你来跟我胡扯。我和她生活在一起，
又不是你。你又不了解她。
I don't? So tell me something terrible.
我不了解她？我是不了解。
那么跟我说说到底有什么可怕的事。
There's nothing terrible to tell you.
那我来告诉你，没什么可怕的事可以告诉你的，
明白吗？我很在乎她，她很不错，知道吗？
I don't wanna hurt her.
That's not what this is about.
我不想伤害她。
我这样做并不是想伤害她。
Suddenly you take up
with a cocktail waitress--
好吧。可突然之间从旁门左道你招来个
鸡尾酒女招待，所以我完全认为……
- She's not a cocktail waitress.
- I think of you and Sally--
- 她不是的…你住嘴，她不是鸡尾酒女招待。
她是个受过教育的好女孩，她非常棒。
- 你知道，我考虑的是你和萨莉……
She's warm and she's nice
and I can relax around her.
她很热情，她人很好，
在她身边我可以很放松。我可以呼吸。
Sally was hyper. You know that.
萨莉有点神经，这你也知道。
She's great, but she's
cold and difficult.
她是不错，但她…她很冷漠，
她…她…她很难缠。
Her Radcliffe friends and the crap
about her decorator.
她的什么“拉德克利夫学院”的朋友，
还有她那些室内装潢的狗屁玩意儿。
I was bored at the opera.
- 嘿，我告诉你好了，我受够了歌剧。
- 嘘…嘘……
She'd never go to a game.
We'd never just relax.
我受够了歌剧。她从不愿意和我
一起去看“巨人队”的比赛。
我们从不会在哪儿坐下来，放松一下。
If I put an ashtray down
in the wrong place, that was it!
甚至在家里我把烟灰缸
放得不是地方，那我就完了！
- It took 15 years to understand this?
- I should've done it before now.
- 你要花…这要让你花15年时间才闹明白吗？是吗？
- 好吧，我是应该老早以前就这么做了。
But we had kids and we're
all scared of being alone.
可你知道…我是说，我们有孩子，
我们也都很害怕独自一人。
I love Sally. But what's
wrong with aerobics?
嘿，你听着。我爱萨莉，明白吗？别误解我。
可我和健身教练在一起又有什么不对？
- What am I? A snob?
- What's it got to do with aerobics?
- 我成了什么人？虚伪小人？
- 这和健身教练有什么关系啊？
Big deal. So she's not
Simone de Beauvoir.
她就是了不起，她成不了
西蒙娜・德・波伏瓦又怎么样？
I want somebody who screams
when I fuck her.
我希望后半辈子好好享受一下，
不行吗？我希望我干她的时候
她的指甲会扣进我背里尖声高叫。
She's a fucking cocktail waitress.
那她就他妈是个鸡尾酒女招待，
她就是鸡尾酒女招待。
That's not your business. You don't
know what goes on between us.
嘿，你给我闭嘴！这不关你的事，伙计！
你根本不懂我们俩之间的事。
I'm tired of being corrected
and criticized.
我受够了被人纠正错误，
被人批评指责。
That's all I ever did with Sally.
我和萨莉在一起时就是这样，
好像我总是在做试演。
And your mother is not in town.
She's in Florida.
你妈妈没来城里，加布，
她在佛罗里达住着呢。
I think no matter how hard we worked,
the marriage wouldn't have lasted.
我真的认为不管我们如何努力，
婚姻也不可能永久维系。
How long were you and Judy married?
你和朱蒂的婚姻有多长时间？
Five years.
五年。
- Why did you split up?
- I thought I wanted out.
- 你们为什么分的手？
- 到最后，我想我不再需要那个婚姻。
I felt I had just run out of gas.
我感觉油箱里已经没油了。
But as I look back, I think
it was Judy who wanted out.
可是现在我回头看一下，
我想其实是朱蒂才不想要那个婚姻。
So she left you?
噢，这么说是她离开的你？
No, she'd never--
That's not her style.
不，不，她才不会……
那不是她的风格。
Don't let Judy fool you. She's
what I call passive-aggressive.
别让朱蒂骗了你，她是那种
我称之为“被动进攻型”的人。
Everything is,
"Poor me, give me a break."
她总是一副“我好可怜啊，
你饶了我吧”的样子。
But she gets what she wants.
可她总是能得到她想要的东西。
I remember when she met her
current husband, Gabe Roth.
我还记得那天她遇见她现在的丈夫
加布里埃尔・罗斯的情景。
My husband and daughter are staying...
这星期余下的时间，
我丈夫和我女儿呆在这里，
...but I'm leaving tomorrow.
I have to work.
但是我明晚必须乘火车进城，
我还有些工作要做。
- Let me give you a lift.
- No, don't be silly.
- 你看，你可以搭我的车，我明天开车回去。
- 不，别傻了，不。
- Why go on the train?
- It's fine.
- 你…你为什么非得坐火车回去？
- 不，我喜欢坐火车。火车很好。
- Would you like something to eat?
- Me? No. I'll get you something.
- 你看，我想去拿点东西来吃。
你呢？你想要什么？
- 我？不…不，还是我去给你拿吧。
- I was just on my way.
- Don't be silly.
- 我正要去。还是你告诉我你要什么吧。
- 别傻了，我给你去拿……
- Pasta? Anything else?
- That's fine.
- 意大利面？还要其他的么？
要喝点什么呢？就意大利面和色拉？
- 可以了。是的。
- I can easily get a cab.
- Why should you?
- 我从火车站很容易就叫辆出租车，
一点问题都没有。
- 别傻了。为什么你非得……？
See? He winds up getting the food.
明白我的意思了吧？
最后还是他去拿了吃的，
He changes his schedule,
drives her home.
他改变了他的日程，
驱车将她送到家了门口。
And all the time it's,
"No, I'll be okay. Don't help me."
她总是在说：
“不，不，我没事的。不用帮我。”
What he doesn't say is that for
the last two years of our marriage...
我前夫没有说到的是，
在我们婚姻的最后两年，
...he was virtually impotent,
when it came to me.
当他想和我干那事时，
他事实上很无能为力。
He was just raging because I didn't
turn out to be what he thought--
他变得很愤怒，因为我没有变成
他所期望我的……
He thought I'd be one thing.
His mother, to be exact.
他以为我会成为那样一种人，
那就是他母亲，准确地说。
And I couldn't take the fact that
he was unromantic in every way.
而让我受不了的事实是，
从各个方面来说，他都极其的平庸。
He'd give you an appliance
for your birthday.
他是那样一种人，他会送你一件
厨房用具作为你的生日礼物。
I never got her a Melior coffeemaker
for a birthday present.
我从没送过她“梅利尔咖啡机”
作为生日礼物。
I got her a camera once.
我曾送过她一个照相机，
And an enlarger
for our anniversary.
和一个摄影放大机，
以纪念我们的结婚日。
She asked for it.
不过那是她要的，她要求我送的。
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么呢？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I was thinking about
that manuscript you're reading.
也许我在想你正在读的那份手稿。
- It's just a terrible novel--
- Very autobiographical.
- 噢，天呐，这是部很糟糕的小说……
- 非常具有自传性质。
- What else can I work on?
- Should I be insulted?
- 嗯…我还可以写点什么呢？
- 我应该被贬损吗？
Why insulted?
为什么你应该被贬损？
The way we met.
That party in the Hamptons?
你描述我们相识的方式，
在汉普顿的那个聚会？
"He spotted her from a distance
and Harriet leapt to mind.
“他远远地看见了她，
头脑里突然跃入了哈丽特的影像。
"He was drawn to her instantly
because she reminded him...
“就这么简单，他立刻就被她吸引住了，
因为她让他想起了…
"...of his only genuine passion.
“…他唯一有过的真正的激情。
"His sixth sense told him
to move on it.
“他的第六感告诉他应该采取行动。
"But she wasn't Harriet. The minute
he met her, the dream evaporated."
“然而她并不是哈丽特。
他结识她的那一刻，他的梦也随之消散了。”
- So she wasn't crazy.
- No, just boring.
- 是的，没错，你又没那么疯狂。
- 是的，我只是令人厌烦。
She's the best.
That's why he marries her.
噢，不，她是书中最好的女人，
这就是为什么他和她结了婚。
- But he pays a price.
- This is junk. I'll throw it away.
- 但是他付出了代价。
- 反正这也是垃圾，你知道，我早想把它扔了。
You're wrong. It's full
of vitality and wit. It's good.
不，你错了。听着，小说充满了
活力和智慧，写得很好。
- You're prejudiced, you're my wife.
- Your dull wife.
- 你有偏见，因为你是我妻子。
- 你的沉闷的妻子。
I don't know why you ask
for my opinion. You don't care.
我不明白为什么你一定要征求我的意见，
你知道，你根本就不在乎我有什么意见。
- It's not true.
- It is true.
- 不是这么回事。
- 就是这么回事。
I think it's a mediocre novel.
我认为这是部很平庸的小说。
You have no respect for my judgment.
If somebody else said that...
因为你根本不尊重我的评判。
要是别的什么人过来这么说，
- ...you'd accept it totally.
- I would not.
- 你一定就全盘接受了。
- 我不会的。
After some time,
Judy and Sally had lunch.
又过了一段时间，
朱蒂有次和萨莉一起吃中饭。
Sally made a surprising announcement.
萨莉作了一番令人吃惊的告白。
I like being single.
我喜欢单身一人。
You do? I had the opposite impression.
是吗？我怎么会有截然相反的印象。
That's anticipatory anxiety.
噢，那只是事前所预料的焦虑。
You realize it's not as bad as you
fantasized. Like pulling a bad tooth.
可当你平静下来之后，你就会觉得这并没有
你想象中的那么糟，就像是拔掉一颗坏牙。
All the festering wounds of your
marriage, the disappointments...
你婚姻中所有那些溃烂化脓的伤口、
那些失望沮丧、
...the resentments, they're gone
in one clean yank and you're free.
那些怨恨愤懑，猛然之间都消失得
无影无踪，你自由了。
After years of accumulating problems
and swallowing one's anger...
你想象不出这会是什么样的感觉，那么多年下来，
积聚了那么多的问题，你忍气吞声，
- ...you have a chance to begin again.
- Yeah. I can imagine.
- 然后你有了个重新开始的机会。
- 不，我…我能够想象。
The clock ticks faster for a woman.
Do it while you have some allure left.
对一个女人来说，时间更加不等人。
你必须得抓紧了，乘着你还有些吸引力。
The one advantage of being older is...
年纪变大有一个好处，那就是…
...you have a lot of experience.
…你有了很多的经验。
I have a better shot
at making things work out...
我有更好的把握，
让事情有更好的结果，
...if I met someone.
如果我碰上什么人的话。
If Gabe and I met now,
knowing all the things we know...
我经常会想，你知道，假设加布和我现在认识，
了解了我们现在了解的所有的事，
...we'd have a better relationship.
No question.
那我们就会有个更加好的关系，
这点毫无疑问。
Would you still marry him?
可你还会嫁给他吗？
God, what a question!
天哪，你这问题问得！
You know, for me, I just--
你知道，对我来说，我只是……
The thought of breaking up
is just so painful.
一想到两人要分手，
真是太痛苦了。
You can't stay out of fear.
You know what you become?
你不应该出于害怕，就硬呆在一起，
因为那样的话，你知道，你会变成什么样的人？
- What?
- My mother and father.
- 什么样的人？
- 我妈妈和我爸爸。
Well...
唔……
...I've pictured myself free.
我…我设想过自己的自由。
- I know you have.
- How do you know?
- 我知道你设想过。
- 你怎么知道的？
Because you got so angry
that night...
因为那天晚上
你一下变得那么愤怒，
...when Jack and I said
we were splitting.
当杰克和我
谈起我们要分手的事时。
I realized we must have
touched a nerve.
事后我想了一下，我意识到
我们一定触到你的神经了。
- No.
- Yes! It's like Hamlet and Oedipus.
- 不。
- 是的！就像是哈姆雷特和俄狄浦斯。
You were angry because I did
what you really want to do.
那晚你很愤怒，因为我做了
其实是你想做的事。
You're over-dramatizing.
Gabe and I are okay.
你过分夸张了，
加布和我还好。
- Nobody has it perfect.
- I know. I know.
- 没有十全十美的婚姻。
- 我知道，我知道。
When it's good, nothing's better.
既然都还好，
那没什么比这更好的了。
Listen, I think maybe I have
a possibility for you.
听着，我想我也许可以
给你找个可能的人选。
- Tell me.
- Michael Gates?
- 告诉我。
- 记得迈克尔・盖茨吗？
The one you said was attractive?
In your office?
就是你说过的很有吸引力的那一位？
你办公室的那位？
He's only been there a few months.
他来这儿才几个月。
He had a girlfriend,
but they've broken up.
我知道他曾有个女朋友，
不过现在他们分手了。
I do think he's attractive.
He's charming, he's bright.
我真的认为他很有吸引力，
他…他很有魅力，也很聪明。
The timing's perfect.
你看，现在时机也正合适。
你还有更好的机会吗？
Come up to the office now
and meet him. See how you feel.
我在想你现在就去我办公室见见他，
看看你的感觉如何。
If you're interested,
we could all...
要是你认为你还有兴趣，
我们可以一起…
...arrange something
or go out together.
…安排点什么事，
比如出去聚一聚什么的。
Michael, this is Sally.
I'm finding some back issues for her.
迈克尔，这是我朋友萨莉，
我要给她找几本以前的杂志。
- She's with the Preservation Committee.
- Preservation?
- 萨莉为“地标建筑保护委员会”工作。
- 哦，“保护委员会”？
I don't believe in capital punishment
except for New York builders.
我这么跟你说吧，我不赞成有死刑，
除了对某些纽约的建筑商们。
Not just New York.
不只是纽约是这样，
There's always a blind passion
for the new, the young.
在哪儿都有对新鲜玩意的盲目热情，
你知道，年轻人啊。
Listen, you two wait here
and I'll be right with you.
听着，你们俩在这等一会儿，
我要去把这复印一下，马上回来。
- Take your coat off.
- All right.
- 把外套脱了吧，那样舒服点。
- 好的。
Throw it anywhere.
We're putting out an issue...
随便扔哪儿。对不起，我这里乱糟糟的，
我正在编撰一整期有关…
...of German furniture styles
in the '20s and '30s.
…德国二十和三十年代
家具风格的杂志。
I hate that period. I did my college
thesis on Bauhaus architecture.
我痛恨那段时期。我大学论文
做的就是有关“鲍豪斯建筑”，
It was called "Function and Fascism."
This was years ago at Radcliffe.
题目叫《功能和法西斯主义》。
那是多年前在“拉德克利夫学院”，你知道。
It was very unpopular. Not that it
won't make a good magazine subject.
我对此大加抨击，所以很不受欢迎。
倒不是说那不能成为杂志的一个好题目。
Have a look at that chair.
Remember that?
看一下这把椅子。
还有印象吗？
- Isn't it wonderful?
- I truly dislike that chair.
- 这是不是很棒？
- 我真的不喜欢这把椅子。
- This one?
- I hated that.
- 好吧，那这把呢？
- 我讨厌这把椅子。
What do you think?
Isn't he sweet?
那么你感觉怎么样？
他是不是很可爱？
- Well, yes. He seems nice.
- Yeah.
- 唔，是的。他看上去还不错。
- 是吗？
- I think he's great-looking.
- And he's single and not gay.
- 我认为他长得特帅。你觉得呢？
- 他单身一人，也不是同性恋？
I'm telling you, he just broke up.
噢，我告诉过你，他才与人分手。
I don't know him that well.
我还没了解他到那种程度。
He's quiet.
I like that about him.
你知道，他…他有点安静。
不过我喜欢他那样。
He's got a great sense of humor.
He's a very charming drunk.
他的幽默感很强。
他醉酒后的样子也很迷人，
There was a party here
and he'd had a lot.
因为在这儿的一个生日晚会上，
他喝多了威士忌。
He was quoting Yeats' poems
and he was crying.
然后他吟诵起叶芝的诗来，
他泪流满面。
He was? He weeps?
- 是吗？他哭了？
- 是的。
But in the sweetest way.
So shall I get us all together?
但是以那种十分可爱的样子。
那么你怎么说？要不要我召集聚一聚？
He already asked me to lunch.
噢，不用你劳神了，
他已经邀请我吃午饭了。
He did?
是吗？
We both took courses at Cambridge.
我们俩都在坎布里奇【马萨诸塞】上的大学。
He suggested we have lunch
next week.
所以他建议我们下星期一起吃个中饭。
因此，你知道……
That would be great.
I'd be the matchmaker.
那太好了！
我…我成了你们的红娘。
I took an instant liking for Sally.
I was immediately attracted.
我一下子就喜欢上了萨莉。
天哪，我立刻就被她吸引住了。
She spoke her mind,
she spoke her thoughts.
她…她直话直说，她心里怎么想
就怎么说。这点我真的很喜欢。
And she's very sexy, you know?
她…她也很性感，你知道。
Look, I wasn't looking
for another relationship because...
你看，我说过我不想刻意
去寻找新的关系，因为…
...I'd just split up with Amy
and sworn off getting involved.
…我刚和艾米分手，
我发誓不想再卷进去了。
But with Sally, there was something
that just hooked in at once.
可是和萨莉，天哪，
有什么东西立刻就抓住了我。
- So you were grateful to Judy?
- Yes, I was. Very.
- 那么你很感激朱蒂介绍你们认识？
- 是的，我很感激，非常感激。
It's funny, you know. When I--
真有意思，你知道，当我……
When I first got to know Judy,
I thought she was flirting with me.
当我一开始认识朱蒂，我有种
隐约的感觉她在向我调情，你知道。
And I thought she must be
unhappily married.
我当时想，她的婚姻一定不怎么如意。
I met her husband, they seemed
fine. That's typical of her.
后来我遇见了他丈夫，他们看上去还不错。
朱蒂给人感觉就是这个样子的。
She's very giving...
你知道，她非常热情，
...and she did me this favour
by introducing me to Sally.
这次她给我帮了个大忙，
介绍我和萨莉认识。
Your second story was as interesting
as your first. It was wonderful.
你的第二篇小说也非常有意思，
一点也不逊于你的第一篇。我认为非常棒。
- Great!
- I was knocked out.
- 噢，太好了！
- 我完全被慑服了，是的。
I'm thrilled.
I'm so glad you like it.
我太受宠若惊了，
我很高兴你喜欢它。
You're so encouraging to me.
I want you to know that.
你的话给我的鼓励太大了，你知道。
我想让你知道这点。
Don't be silly.
I'm just one opinion.
不，别傻了，只是我的一己之见而已。
你知道，反正给我的印象很深。
You're the opinion.
你的意见就足够了。
Your line was great. "Life doesn't
imitate art, it imitates bad TV."
你的句子造得很妙，比如
“生活并不仿效艺术，它仿效烂电视节目。”
- I think it's completely true.
- Right.
- 我想这完全正确。
- 是啊。
I can't tell you how much your
opinion means to me, you know.
我想说的是你的意见
对我有多么的重要，你知道。
Listen, you wanna go for a walk?
I mean....
你看，你想不想去走一走？
我是说……
A walk?
走一走？
- You're busy, right?
- No, no.
- 你有事，是吗？
- 不，不，不。
I just meant for a walk,
to discuss....
我只是想散散步，讨论一下……
You want to hear more
about your story.
噢，你想听到更多的
关于你小说的看法，我猜到了。
The way you structured the story--
The tension built up...
你写得很棒，我是说你小说结构的
组织方式，因为你很完美地…
...beautifully and you released
the energy in the last paragraph.
…积聚了张力，直到最后一段，
你释放掉所有的能量。
- That was very sophisticated.
- Thanks.
- 这真的非常不简单。
- 噢，谢谢。
I spent five days searching for
the word to describe the husband...
我花了五天时间想找一个
合适的词来形容那个丈夫，
- ...and came up with "appucious."
- Appucious.
- 最后我想起了“冲犷”。
- “冲犷”，是啊。
- I couldn't find it in the dictionary.
- I made it up.
- 我…我查了下字典，可没能查到。
- 是啊，我知道，我造出来的。
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, it described it perfectly.
- 哦，是吗？
- 是的，我想用它来形容恰到好处。
Tolstoy is a full meal.
托尔斯泰是一套大餐。
Turgenev is a fabulous dessert.
That's how I characterize him.
屠格涅夫，我得说是一道奇妙的甜点，
我是这样看他的特点的。
Dostoyevsky?
陀思妥耶夫斯基呢？
Dostoyevsky is a full meal with
a vitamin pill and extra wheat germ.
陀思妥耶夫斯基是一套大餐，
外加维生素片和一大盘麦芽糊。
"I fall upon the thorns of life.
I bleed."
“我跌倒在生活的荆棘上，鲜血直淌！”
【雪莱《西风颂》】
I used to think that was so romantic.
我经常想这真的很浪漫。
To write, to fall in love,
and to experience real passion.
噢，用心写作，真诚去爱，
体验真正的激情。
Really? You think passion
could actually be sustained?
是吗？你…你认为激情
真的可以持久吗？
I don't know.
噢，我不知道。
Time magazine said you lose
your sexual attraction...
《时代周刊》上说四年之内，
你就会失去…
...for the other person
in four years, I think it was.
…对另一个人的性方面的兴趣，
我想是这么说的。
Time must know, right?
《时代周刊》说得没错，是吗？
I sometimes think of living in Paris.
我有时候会想去巴黎生活会怎样，
Europe in general.
I find that romantic.
你知道，或欧洲的其他什么地方。
我觉得那一定很浪漫。
I like cafe life. I'd like
to write, get a flat.
你知道，我喜欢咖啡生活。
我喜欢写作，也许租套小公寓什么的。
Sounds great.
听上去很不错。
Walking the streets
is fun in Paris.
是啊，在巴黎的街道上走走
就很有乐趣，你知道。
Until you've been kissed on
a rainy Parisian afternoon...
听着，我跟你说，除非你在一个
下雨的午后，在巴黎被人亲吻过，
...you've never been kissed.
否则你就不能算被人吻过，相信我。
- And were you kissed?
- I wasn't kissed, I was the kisser.
- 那你在雨中被人吻过吗？
- 我…我没被人吻过，但是是我亲吻别人。
Okay, I was wondering...
好吧，我在想…
- ...if I could read your novel.
- How'd you know I had a novel?
- …我能不能读一下你的小说。
- 你怎么知道我写了部小说？
You mentioned it
when we had lunch that time.
唔…上次我们一起
吃中饭的时候，你提到过。
- I'm very disenchanted with it.
- Yes.
- 啊…你知道，我对它一点也没兴趣了。
- 是啊。
I know. I'm only asking you because
I could learn a lot from it.
我知道。我只是想问一下你，
因为我想我可以从中学到很多东西。
I would like to know what you
like and what you don't...
我只是想知道你喜欢什么，
你不喜欢什么，
...and why you're so critical of it.
还有为什么你对它那么不满，你知道？
Let me think about it.
让我考虑一下吧。
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
- 你没事吧？
- 没事。
Let me think about it.
I'll think about it.
让我考虑一下吧，
我…我会想一下的，你知道。
- I shouldn't have asked you.
- No, no, no.
- 噢，我不应该问你的。
- 不，不，不。
- Let me think about it.
- Okay.
- 让…让我想想。
- 好的。
Gabe. He's always picked
the wrong women. Except for Judy.
唉…加布，他总是找错女人，
除了朱蒂。
She's the first sane woman
he fell for. He's attracted...
她是他第一个…你知道，她是他爱上的
第一个精神健全的女人。他总是迷上…
...to the crazies, the nut cases.
…那些疯子，神经病，你知道，
I got a couple of theories about it.
One is that...
出于某种原因。
对此，我有两个猜测。一个是…
...he knows it's not gonna work
and so he suffers.
你知道，在他内心深处，他知道
那行不通，所以他会遭受痛苦。
That kind of atones for some sort of...
那样一来，他似乎就能
为他年轻时候所产生的…
...early-on guilt he's got over--
What, I don't know.
…负罪感，做出某种补偿了――
那是什么？我不知道。
Another is, like all of us,
he grew up on...
另一个是，你知道，就像我们
所有人一样，他受到电影、小说…
...movies and novels where
doomed love was romantic.
…的耳濡目染，在那里面，
未竟之爱总是最浪漫的。
How are things going with Sam?
你怎么样了？
你和萨姆之间进展得如何了？
Great. Absolutely great.
Saturday, we got up.
很棒，绝对棒极了。
你知道，周六，我们起床，
We had a run down by the river.
It was a beautiful day.
我们沿着河跑步。
天气晴朗，光线充足。
It was terrific. I'm down
to a good weight. I'm exercising.
现在我感觉特好，体重减得恰到好处。
她指导我锻炼，
It feels incredible
to get in shape. I eat great.
体形越来越好，感觉真是好极了。
另外还有，我吃得也很好。
Salads, no meat.
Never touch meat.
你知道，我们吃各式色拉，
不吃肉，从不碰任何肉类。
Later in the day, we rented
some kind of a video.
在晚上么，我们也许会
租一部录像带回来，你知道，
Some sort of dopey, funny,
stupid little thing.
就是那种傻不啦叽的、
没心没肺的滑稽片。
Something Sally wouldn't have
allowed. I laughed like hell.
那样的东西，萨莉是绝不会
允许我往家里拿的。我笑到岔气。
I had a terrific time and I didn't
have to feel guilty about it.
我过得非常开心，而且我不会
因此而觉得有什么不好意思。
She's not Simone de Beauvoir.
We argue sometimes.
就像我说过的，她不是西蒙娜・德・波伏瓦。
好吧，我们有时也会斗嘴。
Trust me. It's King Lear. Shakespeare
never wrote about a King Leo.
这你相信我，行吗？那叫“李尔”，《李尔王》。
莎士比亚从没写过什么《利奥王》。
“【黑泽明】《乱》仅上映一周”
Well, Mr. Intellectual. Shakespeare
wrote in English, not Japanese.
行了，“知识分子”先生，
莎士比亚用英语写作，而不是日语。
That's wonderful.
这话太妙了。
I was just gonna make
some cappuccino. You want some?
我想去弄点卡普契诺咖啡什么的，
你要来点吗？
- No.
- You're sure?
- 不要。
- 你确定吗？
I'm positive. Absolutely.
确定，绝对确定。
Don't start getting excited.
I don't have my diaphragm.
你看，你别太激动了，
我还没戴子宫帽呢。
I want to make love to you
without your diaphragm.
我想在你没戴子宫帽的时候和你做爱。
- What are you talking about?
- I was thinking about it.
- 你在说什么啊？
- 我是说真的，我在考虑这事。
I thought maybe I've been
resisting having...
你知道，我想也许…你知道，
也许我以前拒绝想要…
- ...a child too strenuously.
- What?
- …孩子的念头过于坚决了。
- 什么？
- Since when?
- I don't know.
- 什么时候改的念头？
- 我不知道，我不知道。
These are some thoughts
that I've had. Maybe...
我只是…我只是有了些想法，
就这么回事。也许…你知道……
Maybe it would be helpful.
也许这样可以有所改善。
What kind of help
did you have in mind?
- 你心里想的是什么样的改善？
- 我不知道。
Are you unhappy in our marriage?
在我们的婚姻中你不感到幸福？
I don't think about it that much.
Which is probably a good sign.
你知道，我…我没有考虑太多幸不幸福，
你知道，这也许是个好的迹象。
It's late, I'm tired.
Do you want to talk about this now?
你看，现在很晚了，我也很累。
你…你现在真的想谈论这个吗？
All I said was, it was
a good idea to have a baby.
我想说的只是，我认为
这是个好主意，我们要个孩子。
- It's not such a good idea.
- Why not, all of a sudden?
- 我不认为这是个太好的主意。
- 为什么？怎么突然就不要了？
We have some straightening out
to do before we have a baby.
因为我认为在我们要孩子之前，
我俩之间有些事情要理理清楚。
You wanted a baby.
Why are you in a bad mood?
比如说什么？是你一直想要孩子的，
你知道。为什么你的情绪这么糟？
- Do you want somebody new?
- No.
- 你想要个新的人吗？
- 不。
Who? Like who? Do you?
什么人？比如说谁？那么你呢？
- Certainly not a baby.
- So forget it.
- 肯定不是个孩子。
- 好吧，那就算了吧。
- Because I thought you wanted--
- Okay, fine.
- 你看，我这么说是因为以为你想要……
- 好吧，好吧，很好。
Something you wanna say
to me and you're not?
你情绪很不好，还是你有什么事
想跟我说而你没有说？
We don't want to get into something
you can't get out of.
不，我想我们应该谨慎点，免得到时候
有什么事你想摆脱都摆脱不掉。
You don't want a baby, right?
That's what I should--
那么你不想要小孩了，是吗？
我是说，那就是我应该……
- You know I do.
- Then we have to work on it.
- 你知道我想要。
- 好啊，那我们就要努力一下了，你知道。
But not tonight.
Any thought of sex is now....
当然今晚不行了。今晚…
任何与性有关的想法现在都……
- I'm sorry.
- Not your fault.
- 是啊，对不起。
- 不是你的错。
I'm begging you to have
a baby I don't want.
这太疯狂了，我求你要个
连我都不想要的孩子。
- I knew you didn't want it.
- I don't mean it that way.
- 你看，我就知道你不想要。
- 我说这话不是这个意思。
You know, it's late
and I'm confused.
你知道，我是另外意思。
你知道，时间很晚了，我有点糊涂了。
We have a fine marriage. I don't
know what all this talk is for.
我们的婚姻相当完美，我不明白
为什么突然之间会有这样的谈话。
Michael? I brought you a won ton soup
since you were busy.
对不起，迈克尔？我给你捎了碗汤馄饨，
我看你很忙，没去吃午饭。
Thanks, Judy.
You're a sweetheart.
谢谢，朱蒂。
你真对我太好了。谢谢。
- I see you're going to Carnegie Hall.
- To see Mahler's Ninth.
- 我知道你要去“卡内基音乐厅”。
- 是的，要去看马勒的《第九交响曲》。
- Really?
- I hope Sally likes Mahler.
- 是吗？噢！
- 天呐，我希望萨莉也喜欢马勒。
She will. It's my favorite.
Here are some napkins.
当然她会喜欢，那是他所有作品中
我最喜欢的一部。给你一些餐巾纸。
I've got this great place
to bring her to after the concert.
谢谢。我知道一处很棒的地方，
音乐会后我准备带她去。
A little supper joint.
It's very intimate.
那是一家意大利家庭开的
很小的晚餐馆，很温馨的氛围，
- Courtyard, trellis, fairy lights.
- That's beautiful.
- 有个庭院，有格子棚，装饰着小彩灯。
- 不错，非常漂亮。
It is. It is.
是的，是很漂亮。
It's funny seeing someone
who's just left a long marriage.
真有意思，你知道，和一个
刚从一段漫长婚姻中走出来的人约会。
I bet it's been a while since
she was romanced, eh?
我想一定有很长时间她没有
被人献过殷勤了，被人追求过了，嗯？
Yes, I'm sure.
是的，我想是的。
I'm such a square. I'm old-fashioned.
I eat all that stuff up.
我太拘谨古板，朱蒂，你知道，
我太老派了。我着迷于那样些东西，你知道，
Music, intimate restaurants,
candlelight joints and stuff.
音乐、温馨的餐馆、
烛光小馆之类的。
Amy used to say I should
have been born in the 1800s.
我想我不属于这个时代，
艾米以前常说我应该生活在十九世纪。
- She found it all a bit corny.
- No, not at all. It's very sweet.
- 她觉得这些都太陈腐过时了。
- 不，一点都不过时，不，都特别可爱。
You go for that stuff too,
don't you?
是很不错，是吗？
我看你也很中意那些东西，是吗？
- Oh, sure.
- Yeah.
- 噢，当然。
- 是啊。
- Tonight was fun, eh?
- Yes, it was good.
- 今晚很有意思，萨莉，嗯？
- 是啊，是很不错，很好。
And that music was fantastic.
那音乐…太棒了。
I usually hate Mahler,
but it was good.
我通常很讨厌马勒，
不过…不过今晚还行。
The last movement's too long.
最后一个乐章太长了，
我认为他应该把它弄短一点。
The second movement was good.
It began well.
第二乐章不错，当然，
你知道，头开得很好。
- Then it gets sentimental.
- Yeah.
- 然后就变得多愁善感了，你说呢？
- 是啊。
The conductor fought his way out.
指挥都快驾驭不了了。
Dinner was wonderful.
噢，晚餐非常棒，
Although I should teach the chef
how to make an Alfredo sauce.
尽管我应该教一下那厨师怎样做
“阿尔弗莱多沙司”，他做得不怎么样。
- Sorry.
- Want to...?
- 噢，很抱歉你不喜欢。
- 你想进……？
- Is it okay?
- Coffee?
- 好的，我是说，我可以吗？
- 喝杯咖啡？
I'd love to.
我很愿意。
I'm yawning because I'm hyper-
oxygenating. The ride made me sick.
噢，不，我打哈欠是因为我想
多多摄入氧气，车坐得我有一点儿恶心。
I'm sorry. I'm not the greatest
driver in the world.
噢，对不起，萨莉。
我知道我不是这世上最好的司机。
No, your driving was fine,
for the most part.
不，你的驾驶技术还好，
从总的角度来说。不能怪你。
I shouldn't have had the last one.
Three's my limit.
我不该喝那最后一杯“玛格丽塔”【鸡尾酒】，
三杯是我的极限。
I couldn't finish the second.
我两杯都没喝完。
Ah, this is lovely.
啊，这儿…这儿真漂亮。
Very homely. English pine.
It's the finest.
非常的古朴。
英国松木家具，最精致了。
I prefer French.
My decorator screwed me.
我更喜欢法国式的。
我的装潢师给我搞砸了。
It's too big.
I have to get a place in town.
总之，这房子一个人住太大了，
我得在城里再找个地方。
It's funny how your whole life
changes. I'm scared here alone.
你整个生活都改变了，这真有趣。
我…我害怕一个人呆在这里，你知道。
- There's been robberies.
- I bet.
- 这一带发生过很多盗窃。
- 是啊，我想会有。
Do you want to get married again
or do you like being single?
呃…你想紧接着再结婚呢，萨莉，
还是喜欢单身一人过？
I love being single.
我喜欢单身一人。
Because I think certain personalities
just need to be married.
因为…你知道，我认为
有些人的性格就需要有个婚姻。
- I disagree.
- Well, that's what they say.
- 我不同意。
- 可是，他们就这么说的。
Not me. I thought I did.
我不需要。我原来以为我需要。
I do. I do.
I think it's time for me.
我需要，我需要。
我想我应该结婚了。
So why have you never got married?
啊哈，那你为什么从没结过婚？
Oh, I don't know.
I got close...
噢，我不知道。
我…我曾经差点结婚…
...in my 20s once,
but it didn't work out.
…呃…在我二十几岁的时候，
不过不了了之。
- Is wine okay?
- Lovely. Thank you.
- 喝点酒行吗？
- 噢，很好。谢谢。
I want to be alone
for a while at least.
我想一个人，
至少先过一阵子再说。
I want to have a few experiences.
If it happens, great.
我想体验一些新的交往。
如果能够发生什么，很好。
If not, that's just fine.
如果没有，那也没什么。
I'm sure you'll get what you want.
噢，我…我肯定你会得到你想要的。
- You're a very beautiful woman.
- Oh, thank you.
- 你是个非常美…非常美丽的女人。
- 噢，谢谢。
- I can't go so fast.
- I'm sorry.
- 我不能…我不能走得那么快。
- 对不起。
It's just, you know....
只是…你知道，
- It's not my rhythm.
- I understand.
- 新陈代谢，这不适合我的节奏。
- 我理解。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I haven't been in a social situation...
我已经很长一段时间没有…
...that's meant anything to me
in a very long time.
…与人有社交上的往来了，你知道，
这对我来说感觉很陌生。
Thank you.
I'm glad to know you care.
谢谢你，萨莉。
我真的很高兴，知道你是认真的。
I wouldn't be with you...
嗯…我不会和你一起在这里，
...if I wasn't at least
interested in exploring it.
要是我没有一丁点儿兴趣
想要探索这样的可能性的话，你知道。
- Well, cheers.
- Cheers.
- 来，干一口。
- 干。
Tonight's meant a lot to me.
Thank you.
今晚对我来说，意义不凡，萨莉。
谢谢你。
Lovely. That's nice.
很好，很不错。
- What's the rush?
- I'm sorry, I apologize. I'm just--
- 为何这么着急？
- 对不起，我道歉。我只是……
I'm overanxious because
I like you a lot.
我过于焦急了，
因为我非常喜欢你。
Oh, dear.
Michael, what can I say?
噢，天呐。
迈克尔，让我怎么说呢？
I haven't made love
in such a long time.
我已经有太长一段时间，
你知道，没做过爱了。
My marriage, I told you,
was dead. For years.
我的婚姻，我告诉过你，
多年以前就已经死了。
I don't know why. Yes, I do.
The second law of thermodynamics.
我不知道是什么原因。噢…不，我知道，
是因为“热力学第二定律【熵（无序）增加】”。
Sooner or later, everything
turns to shit. That's my phrasing.
或早或晚，所有东西都会变得一团糟。
这是我的说法，不是《大英百科全书》的。
Strange, often one
doesn't even see it happen.
你好像比较特别，因为一般人往往
看不到它的发生。
I did.
我看到了。
That's the part that kills me.
正是因为这让我伤心欲绝。
I was in town working.
Jack was on business, in Chicago.
我在城里工作。杰克那天
因为有事应该离开城里，去芝加哥。
All of a sudden, by sheer accident....
突然之间，完全是由于巧合……
“女性内衣”
- Hi. How you doing?
- Hey, how was Chicago?
- 嗨，嘿。
- 嗨，嗨，芝加哥怎么样？
It was good.
I mean, it was busy.
很…很好。
我是说，很…我很忙，忙死了。
The old guy doesn't want to settle.
我是说，他…和那老家伙谈不拢。
He's a tough old bird, boy.
他是个很难对付的老手，天呐，你知道。
I couldn't bring it up.
我开不了口问他。
I was so hurt.
And so full of rage.
我感到深深地受到了伤害，
充满了…愤怒。
And scared.
我感到害怕。
For weeks...
有好几个星期，你知道，
...I waited for him to say he'd
met someone. He never did.
我等着他开口说他认识了什么人，
但是他从没提起过。
Although I was suspicious,
I never found another incident.
尽管我一直很怀疑，
可我再也没有发现其他的事件。
So I chose to overlook it
and I hoped it would go away.
所以我选择了不去管它，
我希望它会过去。
But it didn't.
但是没有过去。
Because I began thinking...
因为我开始考虑…
...of getting rid of him...
…想要摆脱他，
...and being single.
成为单身。
And things just got worse between us.
我们之间的情况越来越坏。
We put up bigger and bigger fronts.
我们俩戴的面具越来越厚。
Now I'm single.
现在我是单身一人。
And I realize I'm one of those
people who needs to be married.
我意识到我成了那些
需要结婚的人群中的一员。
- Hey! Hey! Come here.
- Hi.
- 嘿！嘿！到这边来。
- 噢，嗨。
- Where are you going?
- Home.
- 你去哪里？
- 呃…我正要回家去。
- Come on, I'll give you a lift.
- Great.
- 上来吧，我捎你一程。
- 噢，太好了。
Come on.
快上车。
- I have a surprise.
- What?
- 我有个惊喜给你。
- 什么？
I don't know if you'll think so.
You can read my novel.
我不知道这会不会让你感到惊喜。
我准备让你读我的小说了。
Oh, great! Oh, that's great!
Thanks.
噢，太好了！噢，那太好了！
谢谢。
- You have to go easy on it because--
- Oh, of course.
- 不过你得十分平和才行，因为……
- 噢，当然。
- Wanna come up?
- Now?
- 你想上来吗？
- 现在？
Meet my parents.
They're so in love with you.
快点。是的，见见我父母。
他们都非常喜欢你。
Don't you wanna see how I live?
What are you doing here?
你不是想看看我的生活吗？
理查德，你怎么在这儿？
- This is why I don't see you.
- What do you mean?
- 这么说这就是我再也见不到你的原因了，嗯？
- 你在说什么啊？
- You're mistaken.
- I wanted to see what he looked like.
- 你误会了。
- 我误会了？我只是想看一眼他长什么样。
You're not what I imagined.
你知道吗？你并不像我想象中的那个样子。
This isn't my boyfriend.
He's my professor.
没错，因为…这又不是我男朋友。
是的，他是我的教授。
- Your professor?
- Yes.
- 你的教授？这是你的教授？
- 是的。
- I'm Professor Gabriel Roth.
- Nice to meet you.
- 我是加布里埃尔・罗斯教授。
- 啊，很高兴认识你。
- Columbia?
- Stop.
- 哥伦比亚大学？哥伦比亚？
- 噢，你歇了吧。是的。
- Barnard.
- How interested are you?
- 巴纳德学院。
- 你怎么这么大兴趣？
- Come on.
- I want to ask you something.
- 你歇了吧。
- 对不起，我想问你一下，教授：
- You seduce all your students?
- I don't know what this is about.
- 你总是勾引你的学生吗？
- 你住嘴吧！
- 我不知道你怎么回事。我只是走上来……
Okay, just go, please.
- 好了，你走吧，拜托了。
- 明白了。真的吗？
- What are you doing here?
- You led me on!
- 我都不明白你为什么在这儿。你来这里干嘛？
- 因为你导致我到这一步的！
I did not!
I told you from day one.
我没有导致你到这一步！
从第一天起我就告诉过你。
When you have her in your arms,
what does she say to you?
- 你告诉我，当你抱着她时，她对你说些什么？
- 噢，你给我住嘴！
- I don't know what to say.
- Why are you acting childish?
- 听着，我不知道说什么好了。我们得走了。
- 这简直是…你为什么表现得这么幼稚，太荒唐了！
- 我应该揍扁你。
You're acting like a 15-year-old--
I'm sorry.
你的表现象个15岁的……
我…我很抱歉，行了吗？
You're sorry.
What do you think I am?
你很抱歉？
那你认为我很什么？
- I don't know.
- Why don't you just go in?
- 我不知道。我只知道你现在情绪……
- 你为什么还不赶紧进去，嗯？
I am. What?
I'm trying to help you out.
我是要进去。怎么？
我只是想帮你一把。好吧，很好！
- I'm cold.
- I'm sorry.
- 我感到冷，我感到很冷。
- 对不起。
This is my mother.
Gabe Roth.
这是我妈妈；
这是加布・罗斯教授。
It is such an immense pleasure.
见到你真是太高兴了。
- That's my father.
- Oh.
- 那是我父亲。
- 噢。
It is an honor, sir.
What can we get you?
十分荣幸，先生。
你需要来点什么吗？
Nothing.
I'm just-- I'm fine.
不需要什么。
我很…我很好。
Just a sedative, if you have one.
Who was that character downstairs?
要是有镇静药的话，那就来一片好了。
楼下的那个人是谁？
I'll tell you about it later.
It's got so sunny all of a sudden.
唔…我过会儿再告诉你。
突然一下子，太阳就这么大了。
We're fans of yours.
We wish you'd still write those...
我们是你的忠实粉丝。
我们希望你继续写那些有趣的短篇…
- Let me take your coat.
- ...funny stories.
- 把你外套给我。
- 你知道，有趣而悲伤的短篇故事。
What were you going to tell me
about that guy?
那么你告诉我
楼下那家伙是怎么回事？他是谁？
I better start from the beginning
if I'm gonna tell you.
好吧。如果要我告诉你，
我想最好还是从头说起。
My father, he had this...
this colleague who was...
嗯…我父亲有个…有个同事，
- ...his business partner.
- This guy was his business partner?
- 他是他的生意伙伴。
- 那家伙是你父亲的生意伙伴？
This is why I have to start from
the beginning. It leads up to him.
不，不。这就是为什么我要从头说起的原因，
到后面我才会说到他。
My father's business partner,
he'd come by the house fairly often.
那个我父亲的生意伙伴，
他来我们家的次数相当频繁，你知道。
And one day, he told me that
he was in love with me, right?
有一天，他告诉我说
他爱上了我，你知道？
I was very flattered,
to say the least.
不管怎么说吧，
我还是感到相当的得意。
He was real bright and single.
他人很…人很聪明，而且是单身。
We started having this affair.
Naturally, we told nobody.
我们就这样开始了这段恋情。
自然，我们谁都没告诉。
I have this friend, Jane.
Her parents were divorced.
你知道，我还有个朋友，简。
她父母亲离了婚。
Her father, Jerry, developed this
mad crush over me, right?
她父亲，杰里，也对我产生了
疯狂的迷恋，你知道？
And before long, I was seeing
both these men.
不久之后，我…我同时
和他们两个人见面。
Instead of being happy,
I was just miserable.
可是，这只让我感到痛苦，
而不是觉得幸福。
I couldn't get my feelings
straight, so I went to an analyst.
我不能理清我的感情，
所以我就去看心理医生。
I tried for a few months
to work things out.
我花了几个月的时间
来努力摆脱这些事情。
Then, one day, he said
he was gonna stop treating me...
然后有一天，我的心理医生说
他打算终止对我的治疗，
...because he felt
it wasn't the thing to do...
因为他觉得他不再适合治疗我了，
...since he was falling in love with me.
因为他也爱上了我。
I was taken with him. You can
imagine, he's quite brilliant.
我对他也很有兴趣，我是说，
你可以想象他相当的出色。
And I started seeing him.
我开始和他约会。
I did. I broke off from the other two.
是的，我…我和另外两位分了手。
Something inside me
told me he couldn't...
可是我内心里有什么东西
告诉我他不可能是…
...be a very stable person,
let alone a good analyst.
…一个很稳定的人，
更别说是一个好的心理医生了。
So I never really let things
get too far with him.
所以我从没有让
我和他之间的事情陷得太深。
Then one night I met Carl.
然后有一天晚上我遇见了卡尔。
He was very sweet and
he really came on with me.
他非常可爱，
而且他真的也非常喜欢我。
I came to my senses.
I said to myself:
我重新恢复了理智。
我对自己说：
"What am I doing with
these older men?"
“我为什么要和这些
老家伙们搅和在一起？”你知道。
So I cleaned up my act
and I've been dating Carl.
所以我快刀斩乱麻，
之后就一直与卡尔约会。
As you can see, Richard is so
unstable. He really took it badly.
可是正如你看到的，理查德那么冲动，
他真的很难接受这一切。
God! You've got material for your
first novel and the sequel...
我的上帝！你有的这些材料都足够你写出
你的第一部长篇小说，外加它的续篇…
...and an opera by Puccini here!
This is incredible.
…并给普契尼的歌剧作脚本了！
太不可思议了。
Yes, but don't you think I'm right?
I mean, Carl, he's fun.
是啊，可你不认为我做得对吗？
我是说，卡尔，他很有趣。
What the hell am I doing
with the midlife crisis set?
我凭什么要和一帮
中年危机组合混在一起啊？
They're all wonderful,
rather accomplished men.
我是说，他们…他们是都很不错，
都是相当成熟的男人。可是……
In the end, I felt like
I was a symbol of lost youth...
最后，我终于感觉到我好像只是
迷惘的青春或未实现梦想…
...or unfulfilled dreams.
Am I being dramatic?
…的某种象征。
我是不是太戏剧化了？
Gabe.
加布。
Rain's birthday is coming
up, and we'd love you to come.
加布，莱恩的生日晚会
马上就要到了，我们很希望你能来。
- I don't know.
- He doesn't want to come.
- 天呐，我不知道。
- 不，不，他不会想来的。
We would love you to come
for a drink. You and your wife.
噢，求你了，我们真的很希望
你能来喝一杯，你和你妻子，嗯？
Mom, he's not gonna
come to my birthday.
妈妈，他不会…他不会
来参加我的生日聚会的。
You've been a great influence
on her. Inspirational.
你知道，我认为长久以来，你对她的
影响非常之大，可以说是你给她的灵感。
Well, she's great.
可她自己就很棒。
I'd consider it an honor
if you'd come by.
要是你能来的话，
我认为是我们的荣幸。
Just as Gabe gave his manuscript to
Rain, Judy also showed her writing.
就像加布把他的手稿给了莱恩，
朱蒂也给别人看了她写的一些东西。
Listen, I finally got around to
reading these lovely poems.
听着，我终于慢慢地读完了
这些可爱的诗。
- You can be honest.
- I am.
- 噢，你完全可以实话实说。
- 我是说的实话。
- It's just a hobby.
- I was moved. They're full of feeling.
- 你知道，这只是我的一个爱好。
- 我很感动，它们饱含着情感。真的。
- What does your husband say?
- I'd never show them to him.
- 你丈夫怎么说？什么？
- 真的吗？噢，不，我从不给他看这些。
He'd be much too critical.
He has very high standards.
他会苛刻得多，你知道，
他的标准非常的高。
- He'd be right too.
- The two you wrote about New England?
- 你知道，当然他是对的。
- 不，你听着，那两首描写新英格兰的…？
There's a graveyard there
where I'd love to be buried.
在“玛莎葡萄园”岛有个很小的墓园，
我希望能被安葬在那儿。
I used to say to Amy,
that's the place I'd choose too.
我知道，我知道那地方。
我也曾对艾米说，那是我选中的地方。
- Do you want to eat lunch outside?
- Sure.
- 你看，你今天想不想出去吃中饭？
天气很不错，你知道，我们可以……
- 当然，我们走吧。
- Are you soaked?
- No. What about you?
- 天哪，你淋湿了吗？
- 不，还好。你怎么样？
I think just my coat.
噢，我想只是外衣有点湿。
- Your hair's wet.
- Is it?
- 你头发都湿了。
- 是吗？
Thank you, Annie.
- 谢谢，安妮，谢谢。
- 不客气。
- That was fun.
- Yes. My hair's a mess.
- 很好玩，是吗？
- 是啊，我头发都乱了。
Listen....
听着，呃……
- Judy, can I speak frankly to you?
- Sure.
- 朱蒂，我可以向你说心里话吗？
- 当然。
- Thanks for introducing me to Sally.
- Oh. Oh, yeah.
- 谢谢你介绍我和萨莉认识。
- 噢，噢，是啊。
- I think I'm in love with her.
- Gee, that was quick.
- 我想我是爱上她了。
- 天，那有够快啊。
Not that she shares my feelings
or ever will.
不过她倒没有和我有相同的感觉，
也不知以后会不会有，你知道。
- She hasn't been single that long.
- Yeah, but it's like...
- 她已经很长时间没有单身一人了。
- 是的，是的，我意识到了这点。可就像是…
...I like someone and can't
wait for the other shoe to fall.
我终于有了个想去关心的人，
我等不及了，要么另一只鞋也快快落下。
You probably had--
也许你有点……
You're just a little gun-shy
from some bad experiences.
你知道，你有点风声鹤唳的感觉，
因为你以往的一些可能是不好的经历。
Is she as terrific as she seems?
她是不是像她看起来那么出色呢？
She is. She's wonderful. She's...
她是的，她很出色，她很…呃…
...honest and decent....
I can't say enough good things.
…诚实、正派，我…
我怎么说她好话都不过分。
Thank you, Judy. You know
I respect your opinion.
谢谢你，朱蒂。我…我…
你知道我多么看重你的意见。
Do you mind if I--?
你看，要是你不介意，我……
I'm just feeling a little funny.
我只是有点感觉不太好，
可能是刚才跑得太猛了。
- I'll get you a....
- I'm fine.
- 我去给你拿点……
- 我没事！
I don't know why I introduced them.
Why did I push them together?
我…我不知道为什么我要介绍萨莉认识
迈克尔，为什么那样使劲地撮合他们？
When obviously,
I had feelings for him myself.
你知道，很显然，
我自己也对他很有好感。所以……
I was just confused.
I didn't know what I wanted.
你知道，我只是感到很困惑，
我不知道自己究竟想要什么。
You look good. You don't get any
older. You work out, huh?
你看上去不错，你一点都没变老。
你一定经常锻炼吧，嗯？
Since Sally and I broke up, I'm single.
I gotta watch it, you know?
你知道，自从萨莉和我分开以后，
我一个人了，我得看好自己的体形。
I saw Sally the other night.
She's dating some guy.
有天晚上我看见萨莉了，
她正和一个男的约会。
Nice-looking.
Claire can tell you.
她介绍我们认识，看起来不错，
他长得不错。不信你问克莱尔。
Yeah, I think--
What was he? He's an editor.
是的，我想……
他是干什么的？他是个编辑。
So....
那么……
What's the deal? Are they
seeing one another or--?
怎么回事？我是说，
他们经常约会吗？还是……？
We don't know.
不，我不…我们不知道。
I'm drunk, so don't hold me
responsible. You gave up a great one.
我喝醉了，所以你别怪我。不过杰克，
你放弃了一个好人，我是说，你放弃了萨莉。
Ken!
He's having a good time.
肯，肯！
他现在也过得不错。
No, he's right. I know.
Look, we were together a lot of years.
不，他说得对，我知道。
你瞧，我们一起生活了那么多年，
She's a great lady.
她是个很好的太太。
She'll be all right. This guy,
Michael something, seemed fine.
我是说，你别担心，她没事的。那家伙，
叫迈克尔什么的，看起来还不错。
- Let's go.
- I'm not out of line.
- 肯，我…我们走吧。
- 怎么…怎么啦？我说错什么话了吗？
You're okay, right? That girl,
Samantha, should be in the Olympics.
你没事，是吗？那位金发女孩，
萨曼莎，萨姆，她应该去参加奥运会。
What do you think?
Are they serious?
嘿，你认为怎么样？我是说，
他们是认真的吗，互相见面？
- Don't know.
- What did she say?
- 不，我们不知道。
- 她说她是认真的？她说什么了？
We didn't talk.
For a few minutes we--
你看，杰克，我们没怎么交谈，
只有几分钟，我们就……
She looked great.
Has she had face work?
她看上去很不错。
她是不是面部整过容了？
- Face work?
- We gotta go. Good to see you.
- 面部整容？
- 肯，我们必须走了。很高兴见到你。我们走。
Where is Sam?
- 萨姆去哪儿了？
- 我们回家去。
If astrology were true,
twins would have the same fate.
- 如果占星术是真实的话，
那么双胞胎就会有相同的命运。
- 它就是真实的！它完完全全、
- It is totally provable!
- From gypsies?
- 完完全全、完完全全可以证明！你知道？
- 怎么证明？吉普赛人的证明？
Why wouldn't it have an influence
on our personalities?
唔…它完全符合逻辑，不是吗？为什么
行星的位置对我们的个性会没有影响呢？
You know who believes this?
My baby-sitter.
你知道谁相信这个吗？
照看我孩子的保姆。
There is more crime
during the full moon.
他们知道…你知道吗？他们知道
在满月的时候犯罪率就会上升，知道吗？
Well, who knows?
是吗？谁知道的？
It's like the
universe knows this stuff.
唔…你知道，应该是那谁…
应该是宇宙知道这些东西。
You guys just don't get
the fundamental basics--
我是说你们这些人都太聪明了，
就是不了解最最基本的常识。
You should meet my baby-sitter.
She doesn't know anyone in New York.
我很乐意介绍你和我保姆认识，
她在纽约一个人都不认识。
- She's been with me two months.
- Fabulous....
- 她来我们家已经有两个月了。
- 太好了，你知道，因为……
- My ex-wife believed in this.
- You should listen to her.
- 我前妻相信这个。
- 那你就应该多听听你前妻的话。
I'm just making a point.
Because, you know...
我想说清楚我的观点：
因为，你知道…
...the position of the planets
is crucial to your life.
…行星的位置，就像是…
那对你的命运非常的关键，你知道。
I can't stress this enough.
And your body--
我…我怎么强调都不过分，你知道。
你的身体……
- Be logical.
- But I'm totally logical.
- 讲点道理吧。
- 可我这完完全全有道理啊！
I would not put a Sagittarius--
我是说，我不会将人马座……
Sam, we gotta go. Come on.
萨姆，我们该走了。行了，行了。
- We're just getting started.
- It was good to see you.
- 我们才刚开始讨论。
- 很高兴见到你们。快点，走吧。
- It's early!
- It's getting later. See you, guys.
- 还早着呢！
- 有点晚了，快点。回头见，各位。
- It was nice meeting you.
- Come on.
- 能认识你们真是非常高兴！
- 行了！老天啊！
If you don't know what you're talking
about, why don't you not talk?
要是你不知道自己都他妈在谈些什么，
你为什么不试着干脆就闭嘴呢？
They don't know what
they're saying!
- 他们才不知道自己在谈些什么呢！
- 他们才不知道自己在谈些什么？
You feel obligated to talk.
How about listening?
你太他妈的觉得这样的交谈
是你的义务似的。你就不能倾听一下？
- I listen!
- That's a novel idea for you.
- 我倾听了！
- 那对你来说是个新奇的主意。
You are so rude.
I can't believe you just did that!
你太…你太无礼了，杰克！
我简直不敢相信刚才你那样对我！
- You're the expert.
- That's the most embarrassing--
- 是啊，你是专家。行了，我们走。
- 你太让我难堪了，你让我丢脸……
Let's get out before
you make it any worse.
行了，在你没把事情弄得更糟之前，
我们还是赶紧离开这儿吧。
- This bullshit astrology. It's stupid.
- It's not stupid.
- 老是扯你那狗屁的占星术，愚蠢透顶。
- 怎么就愚蠢透顶？
I'm sick of listening to your crap
about soybeans and Zen foods.
我烦透了再听到你扯那些垃圾，什么大豆和
禅宗食物啦，还有他妈的什么星宿十二宫。
- Leave me alone. No.
- Get in the car!
- 别来烦我！不！
- 嘿，赶快上车！
- Who do you think you're talking to?
- You wanna embarrass me?
- 你以为你是谁啊，这么跟我说话？
- 嘿，你听好了：你想让我在朋友面前丢脸吗？
They're making intellectual talk,
and you're jerking off about tofu.
他们想交谈一些富于知识性的话题，
而你却坐在那里大拽什么豆腐和水晶球。
- Believe me, they're just stupid!
- Get in the car.
- 你歇了吧，他们才愚蠢透顶，智商为零！
- 赶紧上车，行吗？
- I'm not going.
- You are.
- 我才不上呢！我不上车！
- 不，你一定得上！
- Help!
- Shut up, will you?
- 救命！救命！
- 闭嘴，你给我！
Shut your mouth! Are you crazy?
你给我闭嘴！你疯了吗？
- I wanna embarrass you!
- Embarrass me?
- 我就是要让你丢脸！
- 快进…你要让我丢脸？
- Are you coming?
- I hate you and your...
- 你过不过来？
- 不！我恨你还有你…
...stupid fucking asshole friends!
…他妈的那些脑瘫的混蛋、恶棍、杂种朋友！
Get in.
Get in the car.
上车！
把你屁股挪到车上去，现在！
- Where's my bag?
- I don't know. It doesn't matter.
- 我的包呢？！
- 上车去。我不知道。我才不管呢。
Here. Get in the car.
给你。上车去。
Goddamn, I must have been
out of my mind. You're crazy.
真他妈见鬼！我一定是失去理智了。
你是个疯子，彻底疯了。
- You're too drunk to drive.
- Just shut up and let's go.
- 你喝醉了，开不了车。
- 我没醉。闭嘴，我们走。天哪。
- Goddamn it!
- Look what you've done now! Just--
- 真他妈见鬼！
- 看看你都干了什么！快让……
Let me out of here!
赶紧让我出去！
快让我出去！快让我出去！
- Will you just stop?!
- I'm not stopping.
- 快停下来啊！
- 我才不停呢。
- Get in the car!
- You maniac!
- 快回车上去！
- 你个疯子！
Trying to be cute?
你想找不自在？
No!
不！
- Get in the car!
- No!
- 回他妈车上去！
- 不！
- Oh, I don't believe this.
- No! Help!
- 噢，我简直不敢相信。
- 不！救命！
What am I doing?
Get in the car, you infant!
我这是在干嘛？
回车上去，你个毛头小孩！
Get in the fucking car!
回他妈车上去！
Christ!
上帝啊！
You had an orgasm with Michael
and not with your husband?
为什么你与迈克尔可以有高潮，
而与你丈夫却不行？
I didn't. I was trying very hard.
我没有。我是想要有，很努力地试了。
- I was tense. I came close.
- What makes it so difficult for you?
- 可是我很僵硬。不过我蛮接近了。
- 是什么因素使你那么困难呢？
My mind gets racing with thoughts.
You'd laugh.
我思绪万千，想法一个接着一个。
我告诉你，你可能会笑。
- I get so mentally hyperactive.
- Like what?
- 我的心理活动过于激烈了。
- 比如说什么？
I liked what Michael was doing to me...
我想我喜欢迈克尔跟我做，
...and it felt different
from Jack. More gentle.
感觉跟杰克很不一样――
更加温柔，
And...more exciting.
也更加兴奋。
How different Michael was from Jack.
我想迈克尔与杰克多么不同，
How much deeper his vision of life was.
他对生活的认识更加地透彻。
And I thought...
我想…
...Michael was a hedgehog...
…迈克尔像只刺猬，
...and Jack was a fox.
而杰克像只狐狸。
And then I thought...
然后我想…
..Judy was a fox...
…朱蒂像只狐狸，
...and Gabe was a hedgehog.
而加布像只刺猬。
And I thought about all
the people I knew...
我想起了我认识的所有的人，
...and which were hedgehogs...
他们中谁像是刺猬，
...and which were foxes.
谁又像是狐狸。
Al Simon, a friend, was a hedgehog.
艾尔・西蒙，一个朋友，像只刺猬。
His wife, Jenny, was a hedgehog.
他妻子詹妮，也像只刺猬。
And Cindy Salkind was a fox.
而辛迪・萨尔坎像只狐狸。
And Lou Patrino was a hedgehog.
路・帕特里诺像只刺猬。
【典出以赛亚・柏林的文论《刺猬和狐狸》】
I had the impression that at times...
我感觉有那么一会儿，你有点…
...you weren't quite into it.
你有点心不在焉。
No. No!
唔…不，没有！
I mean....
我是说……
You know....
你知道……
I told you the problems
I've had with Jack.
我告诉过你
我和杰克之间的问题。可是……
No!
不！
It was wonderful.
我感觉很好。
I've hurt your feelings, right?
噢，天呐，我伤到了你的感情，是吗？
Don't get the wrong impression.
I loved it.
我不想让你有错误的印象。
我很喜欢。
Me too.
我也是。
I used to get excited
when we got married.
刚开始结婚的时候，
我曾经会非常的激动。
Somewhere along the line,
it slipped away.
然而随着时间的推移，
那样的感觉不知怎的就没有了。
It's okay.
还好啦。
What? That I'm not responsive?
什么还好？我没有反应？
We had a nice experience.
我们的感觉真的不错。
We had two separate,
nice experiences.
是啊，我们有两种各自分离的
不错的感觉。
- But they were nice.
- They were separate.
- 好了啦，可感觉还是不错。
- 各自分离的。
- No wonder your husband went crazy.
- Very funny.
- 现在我明白为什么你丈夫那么抓狂了。
- 非常有趣。
Oh, come on, Sally.
噢，别这样，萨莉。
- You hungry?
- He said, changing the subject.
- 你饿吗？
- 他这么说，想要改变话题。
Oh, stop it.
噢，别说了。
What was that?
那是什么？
- There's been some burglaries.
- Is the alarm on?
- 这一带发生过一系列的入室盗窃。
- 你把警报器开着吗？
Well, call the police.
- 没有，没有。
- 那就报警，赶快报警。我去看一下。
- Who are you?
- 你是谁？
- Jack, my God!
- You changed the lock on my own house.
- 杰克， 我的上帝啊！
- 你把我他妈自己家的门锁给换了。
- Who's this?
- This is my husband.
- 这是谁？他是谁啊？
- 这是…这是我丈夫。
- None of your business. Leave.
- I don't want to.
- 不关你的事，请你立即离开。
- 不关我的事？我不想离开。
- Are you all right?
- Am I all right?
- 你没事吧？你没事吧？伙计。
- 我没事吧？
Is he living here?
你他妈是谁啊？你究竟是谁？
他是住在这儿吗？怎么回事？
- Don't get upset.
- Is he fucking you?
- 稍安勿躁，稍安勿躁！
- 稍安勿躁？他来这儿干嘛？
在我们的床上操你？
- This is my house, pal.
- Let's not get ugly.
- 这是我的家，哥们，这是我的家！
- 嘿，嘿，别那么丑陋！别弄得不可收拾！
- 迈克尔，迈克尔，你上楼去。
I can talk to him. Go upstairs.
我来跟他谈，真的。求你上楼去吧。
- Where's he going?
- Please. I know.
- 他去哪里？
- 求你了，迈克尔。是的，我知道怎么说。
- You going up to our bed?
- It's not our bed anymore.
- 你要到我们的床上去？是这么回事吗？
- 不是我们的床了，杰克，不再是了！
Listen, you need some black coffee.
Then just go.
现在你听好了，你需要来点黑咖啡，
我这就去弄。然后就…你知道…走吧。
Listen, I want to come back.
萨莉，你听着，我想搬回来。
- You're drunk.
- Oh, please. My life is such a mess.
- 你喝醉了。是啊。
- 噢，拜托。噢…天哪，
我的生活真他妈一团糟。
This is not the place to discuss this.
Please go.
嘿，这不是讨论这个的时间和地点。
你还是走吧！
- This is my fucking house.
- 地点？你什么…这是我的家！
嘿，这他妈的是我的家！
- 走吧！半夜三更的。这他妈的是我的家！
This is my house now.
是我的家，现在。
- I want to start over again.
- That's not possible.
- 我想重新来过。
- 不，那不可能。发生了太多的事。
Sally, can I help?
- 噢，天哪！
- 萨莉，要我帮忙吗？
- Oh, please.
- Would you get lost? What is this?
- 噢，拜托，迈克尔。
- 嘿，你能不能躲远点？这和他有什么关系？
- This is ridiculous!
- I can handle this.
- 他算什么人？护花使者？太荒唐了！
- 我可以应付得了。
- I don't believe this.
- You don't have to. Go.
- 噢，天哪！我不敢相信，我不敢相信！
- 是啊，不用你…你不用相信。走就行。
You.... Listen.
God, I....
你…听着，我……
天哪，我……
This was not all my fault.
It takes two of us--
你瞧，这不能都算成是我的错，你知道。
对吗？我们两个都有份…
- I didn't say it was all your fault.
- You're so hard to live with!
- 我从没说过这都是你的错。噢，拜托！
- …都弄砸了。你不知道
和你一起生活有多么艰难！
I would just break my back
all the time. See? Perfect.
你总是让我有芒刺在背的感觉。得，太好了！
看见没有？她总是…有理由，万事皆有理。
What do you want me to say?
你想让我怎么说啊？你说呢？
Our marriage was full of problems.
I know that.
我的…我们的婚姻满是问题。
是的，这我知道。
Some were my fault,
some were yours.
你知道，有些是我的错，
有些是你的错。
You lied to me, you cheated on me--
- 可是你…你对我撒谎，你欺骗我，你背叛我。
- 接着说！嘿！
Why don't you run upstairs--?
- 你为什么不干脆跑上楼去，直接……？
- 我不知道，还以为互相有爱呢。
- There's a stranger here.
- He knows.
- 房间里有个陌生人啊！
- 他都知道，他什么都知道！
He knows. Swell.
That's perfect too.
他什么都知道。太好了。
真是太棒了。
You show me one couple that
doesn't have problems.
嘿，你倒是给我看看，
有哪一对夫妻会没有问题，你知道。
It's tough. Everybody
has a tough time, you know?
这不是不那么常见的。人人都…很艰难，
每个人都有艰难的时候，你知道？
- What about the one you lived with?
- That's total bullshit.
- 你搬去和她一起住的那人怎么样了？
- 那是个灾难，那完全是个灾难。
- Well, I've met someone I like.
- What? You what?
- 可我遇到我喜欢的人了。
- 什么？你什么？
I met someone I like.
我遇到我喜欢的人了。
What about all the years
we had together?
你怎么…你怎么不想一想
我们在一起生活的那么多年？
Well...
是啊……
...you had no problem wiping them out
when it suited you.
你知道，如果你觉得需要，
你会毫不吝惜地将它们一笔勾销。
But I--
I didn't know what else to do.
可是我…我不知道该怎么做，
我不知道还能做什么。我不知道该怎么做。
No! No! I can't discuss this now.
Please! Go!
噢，不！不！我现在没法讨论这个。
求你了！走吧！
- You'll feel better tomorrow.
- I'm gonna feel like shit tomorrow.
- 你看，你明天就会感觉好多了。
- 我明天会感觉像坨狗屎。
这就是我明天的感觉。
Oh, shit.
噢，狗屎！
Hi. I need to speak to Jack.
嗨，呃…我需要和杰克谈谈。
- You're gonna leave me out there?
- I told you--
- 你…你怎么能就那样把我晾在那儿了？
- 我告诉过你，我……
I have never been treated
this way before!
我这辈子还从没有、从来没有
被人这么对待过！
- Perfect how you ruin a life.
- Then see a psychiatrist.
- 看看你如何彻底毁掉了一个人的生活。
- 那就去看心理医生好了。
- I need to see a shrink, slimebag!
- Come on in.
- 我需要去看心理医生了，你个恶鬼！
- 噢，拜托！嘿，嘿，你别躲，你也过来！
This is about all of us.
你为什么不加入进来呢？
这和我们每个人都有关系，你知道。
- We don't have any secrets here.
- Bullshit.
- 在这里已经没有任何秘密。你什么意思？
- 胡扯淡！你除了秘密没有别的。
- I never met a Scorpio who wasn't--
- Will you stop?!
- 我碰到过的天蝎座无不都是……
- 你能不能不再扯那破玩意儿？
I'm going to bed.
Get out. Both of you!
我要睡觉去了。
出去！你们俩都出去！
What's the big deal?
等一下，到底有什么大不了的啊？
So I did some things wrong.
Does it have to be irreversible?
我是做了几件错事，我叫喊，我行为不端。
可那一定就无可挽回了吗？
The heart raged,
grew melancholy and confused...
内心狂怒而错乱，
越来越忧郁和困惑，
...and toward what end? To articulate
what nitwit strategy? Procreation?
目的究竟是什么？为了说清楚
何等蠢笨的策略？为了繁殖？
It told him something.
How mind-boggling numbers of sperm...
这让他明白了这档子事中的一些事实――
有数目多得令人难以想象的精子…
...competed for a single egg,
not the other way around.
…争先恐后地抢夺一个卵子，
而不是反过来。
Men would make
love with any number of women...
男人当然会不分时间和场合，
与无论多少个女人做爱，
...even total strangers,
while females were selective.
包括完全陌生的女人，
而女人则更加有选择性。
They were catering
to the demands of one small egg.
她们在每一个情形中，
仅仅满足一个小小的卵子的需求。
While males had millions of
frantic sperms screaming:
而每个男人有成百上千万
疯狂的精子，它们奔走呼号：
"Let us out, let us out!"
“让我们出去，拜托，
让我们出去，现在！”
It was like personal ads.
这有点类似在私人广告栏上
登出的那些令人叫绝的征婚广告，
Dozens of requirements followed by,
"Non-smokers only."
每一个都有许多条要求，如果她们
还嫌不够，就附加一条“必须是非吸烟者”。
Feldman longed to meet an attractive
woman with this personality:
费尔德曼渴望遇见一位能在身体上
吸引他的女人，而且具备以下的个性：
A sense of humor equal to his,
a love of sports equal to his...
与他相当的敏锐的幽默感；
与他相当的对运动的爱好；
...a love of music equal to his
and a love of...
与他相当的对古典音乐的热爱，
特别是对…
...Bach and balmy climates.
In short, himself as a pretty woman.
…巴赫以及温和气候的偏好。简而言之，
他要找的就是以美丽女子化身的他自己。
Pepkin married and led a warm,
domestic life.
派珀金结婚养子，有个家庭。
他过着温暖的家庭生活，
Placid, but dull.
Knapp was a swinger.
平静但是沉闷。
纳普是个浪荡公子。
He eschewed nuptial ties
and bedded different women:
他逃避婚姻的羁绊，
一周和五个不同的女人上床：
Students, housewives, nurses, actresses
a doctor, a salesgirl--
学生、主妇、护士、演员
医生、店员――
they all held Knapp between their legs.
随你列好了，
她们都向纳普叉开双腿。
Pepkin, from the calm of his
fidelity, envied Knapp.
派珀金表面上平静忠诚，
内心却很羡慕纳普；
Knapp, lonely beyond belief,
envied Pepkin.
而纳普也很羡慕派珀金，
说来可能不信，他感到孤独。
What happened after the honeymoon?
Did desire grow...
蜜月结束之后会怎么样？
欲望真的会随着时间而增长吗？
...or did familiarity make partners
want other lovers?
还是相互熟悉了以后
会导致伴侣们渴望有其他的情人？
Was the notion of
ever-deepening romance a myth...
我们被灌输着长大的什么感情日笃的
浪漫观念会不会只是一个神话而已？
...along with simultaneous orgasm?
还有什么同步的高潮？
The only time Rifkin and his wife
experienced one...
里夫金和他妻子唯一一次
体验到同步的高潮…
...was when they were granted
their divorce.
…是在法官递给她们
离婚判决的时候。
Maybe in the end, the idea was
not to expect too much out of life.
也许不管怎么说，到最后还是
不要对生活抱有过多的指望为好。
So the book was wonderful.
这书写得太奇妙了。
Entertaining,
imaginative and moving....
噢，它十分有趣，
富有想象力，而且非常感人……
You don't have to say this.
You can be critical. Be honest.
你不用说这样的话。
你可以严苛一点，对我说实话。
You make suffering so funny.
噢，当然。所有那些痛苦，
你却把它写得那么滑稽。
The lost souls running around.
我是说那些卑微而迷茫的
灵魂，东奔西突。
That's funny. I've had so much
trouble with the book.
真有意思，因为我对这本书，
不知道该怎么办才好，真的很难说。
- Has anybody else read it?
- Not exactly, you know.
- 你让其他人读过这书吗？
- 噢，严…严格说没有，你知道。
I'm so thrilled you feel this way.
I can't tell you how encouraged I am.
听着，你这样觉得真的让我非常的兴奋。
我感到大受鼓舞，意义非常重大，真的。
Your feelings
about it are really....
- 你知道，你…你对它的感觉真的…
你知道，当然…
- 我很高兴。
But you are a sucker for my work.
I shouldn't get too excited.
不过你…你对我写的东西情有独钟，
所以我不应该太激动了。
I'm objective and, yes,
I do love the way you write.
噢，不，不是这样的，我很客观的。
我是说，是的，我的确很喜欢你写作的方式。
- I had some criticisms--
- I'm sure you did.
- 我有些意见，可总体来说……
- 我肯定你可以提很多意见，显然的。
What were they?
那…那是什么意见呢？
Nothing serious.
The whole thing was just a delight.
没…没什么特别重要的，
我是说，总的来说读起来相当愉快。
Really? I've had such a love-hate
relationship with this book.
真的吗？你知道，我和这本书
简直可以说是一种爱恨交加的关系。
- Oh my God, this can't be--
- What?
- 噢，我的天哪！不可能啊……
- 怎么回事？
I think I left it in the cab.
噢，我的…我想我把你的东西
落在车里了。
You're kidding! In a taxicab?
Are you sure?
你开玩笑！落在出租车里了？
你肯定吗？噢！
I can't believe I did this to you!
Okay, he was Indian.
我不敢相信，我对你做了什么！
不过，他是个印度人。
You left it in an Indian's cab?
- 司机是个印度人。
- 你把它忘在印度人的出租车里了？
No. He was Armenian.
呃…不，他是亚美尼亚人。
That was the only copy.
- 我简直不敢相信。
- 那是唯一的一份。
- I know.
- You must be joking.
- 我知道。等等……
- 你一定是开我的玩笑。
- Hargopian?
- Mr. Hargopian, Swami Hargopian, what?
- 哈高皮杨【亚美尼亚名字】？
- 哈高皮杨？是的，哈高皮杨先生，
或哈高皮杨【印度教】大师，还是什么？
“小心有狗”
I was totally crushed.
I wanted to die.
我完全崩溃了，我绝对…
你知道，我想去死的心都有了。
This was the
worst thing that happened.
这是…你知道，
这是发生过的最糟的事情。
- You put up a false front.
- The poor girl was wrecked.
- 但你还是为了她而强作镇静。
- 没错，我不得不，
因为那可怜的女孩失魂落魄。
I was trying to bail her out.
我是说，你知道，我还能怎样？
我想让她摆脱窘境。
So this book was very meaningful
to you despite what you said.
所以说这本书对你而言还是意义非凡，
尽管你给她留下了你很讨厌它的印象。
- I guess so.
- And the young woman, Rain?
- 我想是的。
- 那位年轻的女士，莱恩，她怎么看？
Her approbation was
very significant to me.
她的赞许对我来说意义十分重大，
我是说，这我承认。
Why was her encouragement
so pleasing?
为什么她对你作品的褒奖
那么令你高兴？
Your own wife liked it very much
and you gave her a hard time.
朱蒂、你自己的妻子也非常喜欢它，
而你却对她的意见置若罔闻。
I don't know. There was some kind
of rapport I felt here that was...
我不知道。也许我感觉到莱恩
对我的某种…某种友善对我来说…
...meaningful.
…意味着什么。
Hey! Hey!
Somebody found your envelope.
嘿！嘿！有人找到你那信封了。
They're waiting at the house now.
他们现在在家里等你们。过来！
It's-- It's so Freudian.
这…这太弗洛伊德了。
What is?
什么弗洛伊德？
The whole thing, leaving
the novel in the cab.
噢，整个事情，
把小说忘在了车里等等的。
Don't be silly.
It could happen to anybody.
不，别傻了。你知道，人人都会
碰到这种事，当时放错了地方。
No, I think maybe it meant something.
不，我想也许这意味着什么。
- Like what?
- Well...
- 比如说什么？
- 唔…
...I don't know.
Maybe I could have been threatened.
…我不知道。我想也许…我是说
我可能感觉受到了威胁。
- Threatened by my book?
- Yeah.
- 受到了我的书的威胁？
- 是的。
- I'm very competitive by nature.
- That's absurd.
- 我是说我的天性非常…非常好强。
- 这太荒谬了。
Why, because I'm a young female?
为什么啊？因为我年轻、又是个女的？
Don't get angry.
I'm in your corner.
不，别…你别生气啊，
因…因为我对你非常支持。
- I'm your biggest fan.
- Yeah.
- 我是说，我是…我是你最忠实的拥趸。
- 是啊。
I just think I could have been
threatened by certain things.
我在想也许我可能觉得
受到书中写的某些事物的威胁。
Like what?
比如说什么啊？你知道……
Some of the attitudes towards
women and your ideas on life.
呃…某些对待女性的态度，
还有你对生活的看法。
- You told me you loved the book.
- I do. I do love it.
- 可你对我说你喜欢这书。
- 是的，我是很喜欢，是的。
- What were your criticisms?
- Nothing.
- 那你的批评是什么？
- 呃…没有。
Tell me your criticisms.
不，告诉我，告诉我你想批评什么。
I was a little disappointed
with some of your attitudes.
我想我是对你的某些态度有点失望。
Like what? What attitudes? With what?
比如说什么？什么态度？态度怎么了？
The way people just
casually have affairs like that.
你描写的那种人们很随意地
就可以有婚外情的方式。那……
The book doesn't condone affairs.
I'm exaggerating for comedy.
这本书没有为婚外情开脱。
你知道，我只是为了喜剧效果而稍事夸张。
Are our choices really between chronic
dissatisfaction and suburban drudgery?
是啊，我的意思是，难道真的我们只能在
持续的不满和城郊的烦闷中作出选择吗？
I'm deliberately distorting it.
I'm trying to show...
不，你知道，我是故意作了扭曲，
你知道，因为我是试图表明…
...how hard it is to be married.
…婚姻不是那么简单的事情。
You have to be careful not to
trivialize things like that.
可你应该谨慎一些，别像那样
把什么事情都弄成了微不足道。
Jesus, I hope I haven't.
噢，天哪，我希望我没有。
The lead character's
views on women...
还有你的主人公对女性的看法…
...is so retrograde, so shallow.
…是那么的落后，那么的浅薄，你知道？
What?
You told me it was a great book.
你在说什么…？你跟我说…你知道，
你告诉我这是本伟大的书。
I never said great, I said it's...
是的，是很奇妙，
不过我没说过它很伟大。我说它…
...brilliant and it's alive.
…很有才华，很鲜活。
We're not arguing about
whether it's brilliant or not.
你看，那不是我…我们不是在
争论它是否有才华。我是在……
Triumph of the Will was a great
movie, but you despise its ideology.
你知道，《意志的胜利》是部了不起的电影，
但是你鄙视它潜在的思想。
So you despise my ideas?
什么…你这话什么意思？
你鄙视我的思想？
No, I don't despise them.
That example was--
不，我没有鄙视。
好吧，这…这个例子举得不妥。
Isn't it beneath you as a thinker...
好吧，作为一个成熟的思考者，
难道在你的潜意识里…
...to allow your lead character
to waste so much energy...
…没有想让你的主人公
浪费那么多感情上的能量，
...obsessing over a psychotic woman...
沉湎于与一个女人的
那种疯狂的关系吗？
...that you fantasize as powerfully
sexual and inspired...
而那个女人，尽管你把她幻想成
既有超强的性能力，又极富灵感，
...when she was pitifully sick.
但她实际上却是令人怜悯地病态。
I don't need a lecture on writing
from a 20-year-old twit.
听着，我们还是就此打住吧，
因为我可不需要一个20岁的傻冒
给我上什么写作的成熟性的课。
You asked to read my book,
you said you loved it--
是你问我能不能读一下我的书，
我说没问题，你告诉我你很喜欢。
- And I do.
- You leave it in a taxicab.
- 我是很喜欢。
- 然后你把他妈的那玩意儿
忘在了一辆出租车里。
You're weeping, I'm consoling you
and you turn on me.
你在那儿哭，我在那儿安慰你，
可突然之间你却冲我开起了火。
Okay. Well, I must have hit a nerve.
好吧。是啊，我一定触痛你的神经了。
Well, yeah. You know....
噢，是啊。你知道……
I'd hate to be your boyfriend.
He must go through hell.
天哪，我决不想成为你的男朋友，
他一定觉得像是在炼狱。
Well, I'm worth it.
是啊，我自作自受。
- Any trouble finding the house?
- No, it was very easy.
- 你们找到我们家没大困难吧？
- 没有，一点都没有，很容易找。
Please. Step this way.
- 请进，这边走。
- 太感谢了！
I'm so glad you found the house.
很高兴你们找到了这里。
- This was so nice.
- It's fine.
- 这对我十分重要，你真太好了！
- 没事，没事的。
I jumped in the cab and wound
up sitting on it.
- 怎么，你在车里发现的？
- 是的，我跳上车，结果发现坐在了那上面。
我打开车门上车，那里有个信封。所以……
That's so nice of you.
Let me give you some--
- 你真是太好了。允许我给你些…我想……
- 噢，没事。
- No, it's okay.
- Really, I can't--
- 不，不，没事的。
- 你不知道…真的，我无法……
- I want you to stay for coffee.
- No, you're--
- 我想请你们俩留下喝杯咖啡。
- 不，你真是……
- I won't take no for--
- She won't.
- 我不想接受“不”的回答。
- 她不想接受“不”的回答。
- We'll have coffee.
- Okay, good.
- 好吧，我们就喝点咖啡。
- 这对我们来说机会难得。很好，太棒了。
- I'm sorry--
- I'm sorry, it was my fault.
- 你看，我真的很抱歉这一切。
- 不，不，是我该抱歉，这是我的错。
It was totally--
不，这完全是我的错……
If you don't mind my saying,
you have a beautiful daughter.
对不起，罗斯先生，要是你不介意我这么说，
你自己也有个非常漂亮的女儿。
I admit it,
her argument in the cab...
是的，我承认，她的…你知道，
我们在出租车里的争论…
...I found attractive.
It attracted me to her.
…很…我觉得很有意思，那让我觉得
她很有意思，从某种意义上来说。
That she was not a passive,
worshipful pupil.
你知道，她不只是那种被动型的
对你崇拜之至的小学生之类的。
Something in me sensed...
那让我心里面感觉到了一些东西，
...not that I'd
do anything about it...
并不是说我因此就想要怎么样，
当然我也没怎么样。但是…
...I had, you know,
certain daydreams about it.
…我确实因此有了，你知道，
一些白日梦想。
A week later,
Jack and Sally reunited.
不到两个星期之后，
杰克和萨莉重归于好。
This was celebrated over dinner.
为了庆祝这一峰回路转的事件，
他们与加布和朱蒂共进了晚餐。
You can't just wipe out
years of closeness.
你看，你不可能…你根本不可能就这样
把多年的亲密关系一笔勾销。
You think you can.
But the roots are there.
我是说，你以为你能做到，你没有
看到根基，但是天哪，它们就在那儿。
I think some people are just not
meant to be single.
我认为有的人天生就做不成单身汉。
Everybody screws up.
The question is...
嘿，你瞧，人人都会搞砸，你知道，
没人是十全十美的。问题是…
...do you learn from it?
…你有没有从中汲取教训？
然后你会怎么做？
I think the true test is
how you weather a crisis.
我认为对两人关系的真正考验
在于你如何经受住危机。对吗？
Everyone looks great when
everything's going smoothly.
是啊。人人看上去都很不错，你知道，
当事事都很顺利的时候。
It's great. If you can be
that mature, it's great.
这太好了。要是你们能那么成熟，
真是太好了。
It's not that. You just start...
不是这么说的。这只是…
我认为你最终会开始…
...thinking about priorities.
…考虑哪些事情是最重要的，
轻重缓急的问题。
How long can you discuss
physical fitness and the zodiac?
是的。你看，你能讨论多长时间
体形健身和星宿十二宫呢？
And this Michael character
was no bargain.
嘿，你和那个叫迈克尔的角色
也没什么结果，得了吧。
- How was Michael?
- I don't know, he was sick.
- 迈克尔怎么样了？
- 我不知道，他病了，他请了病假。
I gave him a call and he did sound
very terrible.
我给他打过电话，他听上去的确很糟，
我不知道，他感冒了。
I guess I really pulled the rug
out from under him.
你很关心他。我想我真的
对他来了个釜底抽薪。
Although his real crush is on Judy.
尽管，你知道，他真正的兴趣
是在朱蒂身上。
- Not to offend you, Gabe.
- I'm not.
- 不是想冒犯你，加布。
- 你没有。我…我……
I love it when someone likes Judy.
你知道，我喜欢有什么人
对朱蒂抱有好感。
Gabe needs confirmation
of his feelings when it comes to me.
嗯，加布总是需要靠别的什么
来证实他的感情，特别是与我有关的。
That's a terrible thing to say.
- 你这样说真是太糟糕了。
- 没错，我说的没错。
I'd watch it if I were you, Gabe.
不，真的。如果我是你，
我一定会多长个心眼的，加布。
He always talks about Judy
in hushed tones.
他在谈到朱蒂时，
语气总是显得很深沉。
I think those poems you wrote
impressed him.
我认为是你写的那些诗，
给他留下了深刻的印象。
Here's to a good marriage.
嘿，嘿，嘿，行了。
为他俩的美满婚姻祝福，哈？
- The best two people can hope for.
- Absolutely.
- 两个人最终能指望的也就是这个了。
- 说得好。
- I didn't know about the poetry.
- I didn't think you'd care.
- 我不知道你还在玩一点诗歌。
- 我以为你不会感兴趣。
- Well, why not?
- Because.
- 唔，为什么不会？
- 因为…
I'd be embarrassed
to show you my stuff.
我告诉你吧，我会很窘的，
给你看我写的东西。
- Why?
- You're so hard on everything.
- 为什么啊？
- 因为你对什么事情都那么刻薄。
What are you talking about?
- 我没有！你在说什么啊？
- 你就是的。
- You're very, very judgmental.
- I like poetry.
- 你特别特别喜好陟罚臧否。
- 我不喜好陟罚臧否，我喜好诗歌。
I'm crazy about Shakespeare
and Byron and T.S. Eliot.
我喜好…你知道，我对莎士比亚、拜伦、
和T・S・艾略特都很着迷。
Well, my stuff isn't
quite that good yet.
噢，是啊，可我的东西
还没好到那个地步好吧。
- I'd give an objective evaluation.
- I don't want an objective evaluation.
- 可我会给你作一个客观的评价。
- 我不想要什么客观的评价。你知道？
I'd like something a little more
supportive and generous.
我只希望能有更多一点的支持、
更多一点的宽容。
- From that character in your office?
- He's not a character.
- 你从你办公室的那个角色那里得到了？
- 他不是一个角色。
- Are you in love with him?
- No! Why, because I show him my poems?
- 你爱上他了？
- 没有！为什么？因为我给他看我写的诗？
- I saw Dr. Ritchie today.
- Oh, where?
- 我今天见到里奇医生了。
- 哦，在哪儿？
I went back into psychotherapy.
我重新去作心理治疗了。
You don't need psychotherapy,
and certainly not with her!
天呐，你开玩笑！你根本不需要心理治疗，
特别是由她给你治疗！
Why? Because she's postmodern?
你只是觉得受到了她的威胁，
因为她比较后现代。
Anyone who thinks the Sabine women
had it coming to them--
听着，她居然写出那样的论文，声称
萨宾族的女人故意让罗马人将她们掳走。
That's not it.
- 不是这么回事。
- 老天哪！
- I don't flirt.
- Don't tell me that.
- 我没有调情！
- 别跟我说你没有调情，
I've seen you do it.
因为我正好看到你了，在晚会上。
You put on a different personality.
你换上了完全是另一个人的个性。
- You're crazy.
- You pretend to want things you don't.
- 噢，你疯了！
- 你当然做了，你变得那么深情款款，
装作想要那些你根本受不了的东西。
- Like?
- Going to Europe.
- 比如说什么啊？你在说什么啊？
- 比如说搬到欧洲去住。
That's flirting. You couldn't survive
off the island of Manhattan.
那只是你的调情手段而已，
你离开曼哈顿岛之后活不过48小时。
You misrepresented yourself to me.
我来告诉你，在我们结婚时，
是你没有如实展现你自己，
What do you mean by that?
- 我对你一直很诚实。
- 你这话是什么意思？比如说什么？
Like you had one child then
decided that was it.
比如说什么？比如你说你已经有了个孩子，
你不想再要了，说那已经足够了。
- I'm not the same person I was.
- That's why relationships go sour.
- 我是这样看待事情的――
人是会变的，我也不是多年前的那个我了。
- 是啊，这就是为什么
我们的关系会出岔子的原因。
- You hate change.
- Change equals death.
- 是啊，你讨厌变化。
- 我当然讨厌变…变化就等于死亡。
Bullshit. That's bullshit!
- 那意味着死亡！
- 这算什么鬼话啊！你真会胡扯淡！
Maybe your students think it's
insightful, but it means nothing.
也许你可以唬弄你20岁的学生，让他们以为
那是什么深刻的见解，可其实毫无意义。
Life is made of change.
生命就是由变化构成。
If you don't change,
you just shrivel up.
变化…要是你没有变化，
你就不会成长，你只会枯萎下去。
I don't want to.
You get sexual at the oddest times.
- 我不想做爱。你总是在
最奇怪的时机想到要性。
- 你为什么那么紧张？
You use sex to express every
emotion but love.
你的…你利用性来表达
任何其他的感情除了爱。
You were attracted to me...
你被我吸引…
...because in some way,
I reminded you of Harriet.
…因为从某种意义上来说――我从来没想明白过
这是为什么――但从某种意义上来说，
我让你想起了哈丽特。
But I disappointed you
because I was too normal.
可是后来我让你失望了，
因为我太正常了。
I liked you because
you were decent and not crazy.
我被你吸引是因为你很稳当、
你很正派、你不疯狂。
- And you found that too boring.
- No...
- 是啊，可你觉得那太无趣了。
- 不！
...as it turns out you were
as crazy as her.
因为到头来，你和哈丽特一样疯狂，
尽管你是以你那平静的方式。
- So I did remind you of Harriet.
- No...
- 你瞧，我确实让你想起了哈丽特。
- 不…你看…
...I had a feeling you
were unstable.
我的第六感告诉我，
某种第六感对我说你也很不稳定。
On the surface you were...
可从表面上看，你好像很稳定，
...but now that we're having problems,
you're not.
但既然现在我们之间出了那么多问题，
所以说明你不稳定。
从表面上看你好像是，但其实不是。
This is all very clear to me.
整个情况在我看来已经相当清楚了。
--we both couldn't sleep one night,
remember...
呃…有天夜里，我们俩都睡不着觉。
还记得吗？
...and we found Wild Strawberries
on cable...
我们看到有线电视台
正放着电影《野草莓》，
...we stayed up all night watching it?
That was great.
我们整晚没睡，就在那里看。还记得吗？
真的很棒，那时刻感觉真的很不错。
We were going to the faculty dinner
and we were on Fifth Avenue...
还有次我们要赴我同事的晚餐会，
我们走在第五大街上，
...on an icy black night.
We were walking downtown.
那是个冰冷漆黑的夜晚，
我们在城里走着。还记得吗？
Suddenly we decided not to go
to the dinner...
突然间，我们决定不去赴宴了。
我们说去他的吧，
...it was such a beautiful night.
We walked into Central Park.
这是个多么美丽的夜晚。我们走进了
“中央公园”。你知道，地上满是积雪。
You could see every star. You were
so beautiful in that black dress.
那天夜里，你可以看到满天的星星。
你穿着那件黑色的晚装是那么的漂亮，真的。
- Don't do that.
- Why not?
- 别这样。
- 为什么？
Because it's over and we both know it.
因为已经结束了，我们俩都清楚。
Do we?
是吗？
All that stuff--
Those memories, they're just memories.
是的，你知道，所有那些东西――
那些记忆，它们只是记忆而已。
They're from years gone by.
那…那都是多年以前的事了。
They're isolated moments...
它们只是一些星星点点的时刻，你知道，
...they don't tell the whole story.
它们并不…并不意味着所有的…一切。
Several days later,
Gabe moved into a hotel.
几天之后，加布从公寓里搬了出来，
住进了一家旅馆。
I wasn't being totally honest with Gabe.
不，我没有完全向加布说实话。
Because I didn't want to hurt him.
But I knew what I wanted.
因为我不想伤害他。
但…但我确实知道我想要什么。
I was in love with Michael.
I wanted to be free to...
唔…我爱上了迈克尔。
我只是想获得去追求的…
...pursue that and not have to lie
or sneak around or anything.
…自由，而不是不得不说谎和欺骗，
或到处偷偷摸摸的。
How could I be 100% honest with Judy?
我怎么可能…你知道，百分之百地
对朱蒂诚实呢？
I loved her
and I didn't want to hurt her.
我…你知道，我觉得我爱她，
我…我不想伤害她。
What am I gonna say?
所以我该…我该说什么呢？
That I'm becoming infatuated
with a 20-year-old?
说我自己已经感觉
被一个20岁的女孩子迷上了？
That I see myself sleepwalking
into a mess?
说我…你知道，说我眼瞅着自己梦游进一堆麻烦？
说我这么多年下来，什么教训都没学到？
Then why didn't you stop yourself?.
那你为什么不就此打住呢？
There was something in my marriage
that I was not getting. Rain--
在我的婚姻中，我渴望有些东西，
但是我没有得到。莱恩……
- There was excitement there.
- Rain had a boyfriend.
- 你知道，她身上有某些令我激动的东西。
- 莱恩有男朋友。
I know. Everything about
it was wrong.
我知道。相信我，
这一切都不对劲，这我知道。
That did not deter me.
但是…你知道，那并没有阻止我。
If anything, as usual,
there was something interesting.
我是说，要是有什么事…像以往一样，
你知道，要是有什么事也许会很有意思。
So, what is it?
You have a self-destructive streak?
那么到底是怎么回事呢？
你有自我毁灭的倾向？
I don't know. My heart...
你知道，我不知道。我的内心…
...does not know from logic.
…不会按逻辑行事，你知道，它只会……
Hello?
喂？
Oh, Michael, please.
噢，迈克尔，求你了！
I can't keep discussing this.
你看，我们…我不可能一直谈论这个。
It was a decision I needed to make--
No. Wanted to make.
我是说，这是我觉得我必须作出的决定。
不，是我想作的。噢，抱歉。
I said I'm sorry.
I can't keep discussing this.
我不行。我已经说过很多次对不起了。
我不能一直讨论下去。
No. I don't want to have a drink.
I have to go.
不，我不想去喝一杯。
我得挂了。
Well, you make it hard!
I have to go.
是你自己给自己找的难受！
我得挂了。
Later, Judy helped Michael get
over the loss of Sally.
一两个星期过去了，朱蒂帮着迈克尔
克服失去萨莉的痛苦。
Here we go.
来了！
- Heavens, Judy.
- Pretty good, huh?
- 噢，天哪，朱蒂！
- 相当不错，嗯？
That's mine, where's yours?
那是我的，你的在哪儿？
I am so happy that's not true.
我很高兴那不是真的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Right, shall I be mum? Cheers.
- 好了，我给你到好了酒。来，干杯！
- 干杯！
- It's a real treat.
- You're welcome.
- 今天你真是盛情款待。
- 你别客气。
- Where's your wife?
- We're not together anymore.
- 你妻子在哪儿？她来了吗？
- 不，不，我跟你说实话，我们不再在一起了。
Oh, you writers. You're so....
噢，你们这些作家啊！你们太……
Happy birthday!
生日快乐！嗨，你怎么样？
Did you meet that woman Jessica?
你见过那女的杰西卡吗？
她女儿和我……
No, I met Angela, though.
不，没见过。不过我碰到了安吉拉。
- Did you see that?
- What?
- 天哪，你们看到那个了吗？
- 什么？
It's incredible, this time of year.
太不可思议了，现在这个季节。
Oh, I love storms.
- 噢，我喜欢暴风雨。
- 看上真的很壮观。
They said we were supposed to
get some of that hurricane.
你知道，电视上说我们会被
卡罗来纳飓风的尾巴扫到。
- It's really coming down heavy.
- How fitting. I was born in a storm.
- 现在雨下得越来越大了。
- 真是太合适了，我就是在飓风中出生的。
It's dangerous.
这太危险了。
She looks great.
她看上去很棒。
She's 21!
It's absolutely incredible.
天哪，她21岁了！
这绝对令人难以置信。我……
- Our littler Rainer.
- I'm gonna be 55.
- 我们的小莱纳，嗯？
- 我都快要55了。
It's our 25th wedding anniversary in June.
到六月份，就是我们结婚25周年纪念。
Don't worry.
We got some light in here for you.
别担心，别担心。
这里有烛光给你们。
I know I paid that bill.
我记得我买过的。
Take some of these candles out there.
把这些蜡烛拿到外面去。
I can't believe this.
I know I had a flashlight.
我不敢相信。
我记得我有个便携灯。
Oh, this is just my luck on my own
birthday. It goes black.
噢，这就是我的生日，太倒运了。
现在一片漆黑。
You look very pretty in candlelight.
嘿，在烛光下你看上去相当相当漂亮。
Oh, did you see the lightning flashes?
- 噢，天哪，你看见那闪电没有？
- 我要喝醉了。很不错，很棒。
It's supposed to get worse. How's
everybody gonna get home now?
我估计天气会更糟，
我不知道大家到时候怎么回家。
Happy birthday.
生日快乐。
I didn't want to give it to
you in the other room because...
整个晚上我一直把这揣在身上，
人人都在那个房间里给你礼物，因为我想…
...it could be misconstrued, so...
你知道，人们可能自然会想…
这可能会引起误解，所以…
- ...I've been hiding it in my jacket.
- Very nice.
- …我一直把它藏在我的上衣里。
- 很漂亮。
That's lovely!
噢，天哪，太可爱了！
That is so pretty.
太美了！
Happy birthday.
生日快乐。
- Why would it be misconstrued?
- It would just look funny.
- 为什么这会引起误解？
- 你知道，因为这看起来有点搞笑，我认为。
Because you have a boyfriend.
你有男朋友。
要是我给你这个浪漫的八音盒，
People wouldn't understand.
你知道，人们会不理解的。
It wouldn't look funny at all.
It's beautiful.
这看上去一点都不搞笑。
它很漂亮。
- You know what I'd really like?
- What?
- 你知道我想要…我真的想要什么吗？
- 什么？
A nice birthday kiss.
一个美好的生日之吻。
- You want a birthday kiss?
- Yeah.
- 你想要一个生日之吻？
- 是的。
Happy birthday.
生日快乐！
- That's all?
- I'm drunk. This is not funny.
- 这就完了？
- 我真的醉了。因为这可不好玩。
What do you mean?
That was a birthday kiss.
什么？怎么啦？你什么意思？
这是完了，这就是生日之吻。
You want me to stick
my tongue down your throat?
你想要我怎么做？让你弯腰后仰，
把我的舌头伸进你的喉咙，直抵你的鞋面？
Come on, you know what I mean.
不，得了，你知道我什么意思。
You got a boyfriend in the other room.
我不能给你那样的生日之吻。
你疯了！你男朋友就在隔壁房间。
I know. It's not serious.
It isn't serious.
我知道。那不是认真的，
我们不是认真的。
Listen, I can't even
have this conversation.
听着，这太疯狂了。
我甚至不应该有这样的谈话。
Not that I haven't thought about it.
倒不是说我没设想过这个，
我的确设想过。
I have, but it's just too crazy. I--
我想过的。可是，你知道，我…
这有点太疯狂了。我……
It's so disappointing.
这太令人失望了。
It isn't disappointing.
You got a boyfriend.
为什么这太令人失望？
你已经有…男朋友了。
You couldn't ask for a
more romantic moment.
因为…我不可能有
比这更加浪漫的时刻了。
I mean, it's my 21 st birthday, and...
我是说，这是我的21岁生日，
...we're in a storm,
the lights are out and there's...
我们正处在暴风雨当中，
外面电闪雷鸣…
- ...the rain sweeping the skyline.
- Why do I hear...
- …风雨交加，正横扫过纽约的天际。
- 噢，天哪，别这样对我！
...$50,000 worth of psychotherapy...
- 为什么我现在花五万美元拨911来…
- 真的非常奇妙。
- ...dialing 911 now?
- It's magical. I'm sorry.
- …接受心理治疗？
- 好吧，对不起。
I'm sorry. I've had a
little too much to drink too.
对不起，我很抱歉。
我也有点喝得太多了。
- Me too. I had....
- I'm just....
- 我也是。我喝了……
- 是啊，我只是……
You want to kiss?
I mean, you want a real kiss?
那么你想要亲吻？
我是说，你想要一个真正的亲吻？
You want an actual,
professional kiss?
你想要…你想要一个实实在在的、
非常专业的亲吻，是吗？
- Yes.
- Both lips, upper and lower.
- 是的。
- 双唇都用上，上下…
- At once?
- I've thought about it.
- …一起来？
- 是的，我真的想象过，
- I gotta tell you.
- Come here.
- 我可以告诉你。
- 过来。
I was just hoping that lightning
can't come into a penthouse...
我能想到的只是，
我希望闪电不会击穿阁楼，
...because it was tumultuous outside.
It was crashing all around and...
因为我以前从没在阁楼呆过。
外面喧嚣狂乱，暴风雨正四处肆虐。
...the scene had to be played.
I mean, I was...
你知道，当时的情景，使人不由自主地
想有些戏剧化的发展。我是说，我……
...I wanted to kiss her,
it was pouring...
她非常可爱，我想亲吻她。
你知道，外面大雨滂沱，
...but I figured,
any second the lightning...
闪电在露台上来回乱窜，
我在想，它随时都有可能击穿玻璃…
...would come right
into the apartment and...
…打到房间里来，
那样的话…
...and that I would die.
…我就会死掉。
I don't want to spend Sunday together,
because I need time alone!
朱蒂，别来管我。我不想一起过星期天，
因为我需要有一个人的时间。
- Be alone! I'm not pushing you.
- Yes. Yes, you are, in that...
- 那就一个人好了！我又不会逼迫你。
- 是的，会的，你会逼迫我，
...quiet, steady way of yours.
"Supportive," is your word.
以你特有的那种平静而坚定的方式。
你总是在那儿等着我，
用你的话说就是“支持”…
"Understanding."
Stop being so understanding.
…“理解”。天哪，
求你别再如此深地理解我了！
I still have feelings for Sally.
我很抱歉，行吗？我仍然经常想起萨莉，
我仍然对她怀有感情。
Feelings I don't think
I could ever have for you.
我想我从来也没有
对你产生过那样的感情。
Oh, God! Where are you--?
Oh, for--
噢，天哪！你要去哪……？
噢，见鬼…朱蒂！
- I'm sorry.
- I never want to see you again!
- 朱蒂，对不起，我真的非常抱歉！
- 我永远也不想再见到你！
- I need you.
- It's good to know how you feel.
- 别那么说，朱蒂，我需要你。我需要你！
- 很好，你让我知道了你真实的感受。
I'm glad to know.
- 可那不是我真实的感受，
我只是有点心烦意乱，亲爱的。
- 我很高兴你让我知道。
- You are so self-centered!
- I know.
- 你太自私了！你太自我为中心了！
- 我是的，我知道。
I didn't mean those things.
- 令人恶心！
- 你别误会，那些话不是我真正的意思。
- Why did you say them?
- I'm confused.
- 那你为什么对我说？
- 我那样说是因为我很困惑，我很心烦。
- I never want to hurt you.
- Bullshit!
- 天哪，我绝不会再伤害你了。
- 胡扯！
It's not bullshit. I don't
deserve you. I'm sorry. Please!
没有胡扯。我配不上你。
我很抱歉。求你了！
- Did you shut the windows?
- I was thinking...
- 你把所有窗户都关好了吗？
- 是的。我正在想…
...it's a good thing we fixed
that leak in the den.
你知道，我们修补好了窝棚上
那个漏雨的小洞，真是件好事情。
Even now I'm still scared of thunder.
Any loud noise.
真太不正常了，经过了这么多年，
我依然害怕打雷，和任何大的动静。
We would have been nuts to
use those theatre tickets.
我们绝对是疯子，要是这种天气
还去剧院把那两张戏票花掉。
We'd have been swerving all over.
你知道，我们一路上会一直打滑的。
- I'm glad we stayed home.
- Me too.
- 妈的，我情愿留在家里。我也是。
- 我很高兴我们留在了家里。
When we were apart,
this storm would have terrified me.
你知道，要是我们已经分开，这样
雷雨交加的夜晚一定会把我吓坏的。
I was scared enough sleeping alone.
一个人睡觉太让我害怕了。
Sometimes you can be alone
when you're with someone.
你知道，有的时候，即使你和
某个人在一起，可你还是会觉得孤独。
Should we have given those
other tickets to Gabe or Judy?
你认为我们是否应该把昨晚
另外的票送给加布或朱蒂？
- We did buy them for them.
- Yeah, I know, but...
- 我是说，我们本来就是给他们买的。
- 是啊，我知道，可是…
...the situation's
completely different now.
- …现在的情形完全…完全不同了。
- 是啊。
A year and a half later,
much had occurred.
一年半以后，
又发生了许多事情。
Judy was married to Michael.
朱蒂离了婚，并嫁给了迈克尔。
- So, you happy?
- Go ahead.
- 这么说，你们很幸福？
- 你来说。
Yes, I think things have
gone pretty smoothly.
是的，我想一切都进展得颇为顺利。
- He puts up with my idiosyncrasies.
- No, she puts up with mine.
- 迈克尔容忍了我的许多癖好。
- 不…不，是她容忍了我的。
She's passive-aggressive.
Somehow, she gets what she wants.
你瞧，我告诉过你，她就是被动进攻型的。
不知怎的，她总能得到她想要的。
She wanted me, she wanted Gabe...
她要过我，她要过加布，
...she wanted the job at the magazine,
out of her marriages...
她要过杂志社的工作，
她要过两次离婚，
...she wants Michael....
现在她要的是迈克尔……
I disagree.
我不同意，不。
When Sally went back to Jack,
I went after Judy.
当…当萨莉回到她丈夫身边，
我就开始追求朱蒂。
Not at first, but when I
decided, I went after her.
我是说，一开始并不这样，可是…
一旦我作出了决定，我就紧追不放了。
Gee, I hope I didn't push.
I wanted it to work, it's true.
是啊，天哪，我希望我没有逼他。
你知道，我希望我们能成，这没错。
We're doing fine. Really.
We've learned to...
我们…你知道，我们过得还好，真的，
我们过得很好。我们学会了…
...tolerate our problems more.
Don't you think?
…更加容忍相互间的问题。
你认为呢？
I've learned, anyway, that love is...
总之，我学到的是，爱…
...not about passion and
romance necessarily.
…不一定非得与
激情和浪漫相联系。
It's also about companionship and...
爱同样也包含了相伴和……
...it's like a buffer against
loneliness, I think.
你知道，它就像是个
抵御孤独的缓冲器，我想是。
That stuff is important.
Somebody to grow old with.
那东西真的相当重要，
你知道，与一个人相伴到老。
What kills most people is
unreal expectations.
想想什么东西那么难对付，令大多数人
寻死觅活的？那就是不切实际的期望。
What about things that
can't be talked about?
那那些不太好开口说的事情
怎么样了呢？
Like sexual problems, for instance.
举个例子，比方说性方面的问题。
- Unresolved.
- Unresolved?
- 没有解决。
- 没有解决？
Well, there's some things you
can't solve and then...
是啊，总有些事情你是
没办法解决的，所以…
...you have to live with it.
…你也只好将就着了。
You construct some
kind of patchwork thing.
你构建起某种补救的东西。
- But sometimes they flare up.
- They do, and when it happens...
- 可有的时候它们还是会爆发出来。
- 的确是，当发生那样的事时，
...it gets tough
when that happens.
是的，那就有点艰难了，
当发生那样的事时，反正不太妙。
You learn to deal with it and then
push it under the rug.
但是你要学会怎么处理这些问题，
然后将它们重新扫回到地毯之下。
And it works. That's the weird thing.
It's not bad.
你知道，那样很管用。
就这么奇怪，那样能行得通。
所以这就行了，这就很好。
You can't force yourself to
conform to some abstract...
我的意思是，你不能硬逼着你自己
去遵从某种抽象的…
...vision of love, or...
…爱的幻想，或者…或者…
...you know, marriage.
Every situation's different.
…你知道，婚姻。
每一种情况都各不相同。
Whatever works is the deal.
你瞧，只要管用就行了。我是说，
戏法人人会变，各有巧妙不同。
Ours is just one way.
我们有我们的方法，
别的人有别的人的窍门。
It's funny. Last year when
we were at Gabe and Judy's...
你看，真有意思。去年的那个晚上
我们在加布和朱蒂家，
...and we announced so flippantly
we were splitting....
- 那么轻率地就宣布了我们打算分手。
- 愚蠢。荒谬。
- I wasn't that confident.
- I wasn't either.
- 在我内心里，我那时其实没什么信心。
- 我当然也没有。愚蠢。
I remember thinking
they were so lucky.
我记得我当时特别羡慕他们，
认为他们太幸运了，
They had such a great marriage.
他们的婚姻太美满了。
It's ironic that we're
together and they aren't.
是啊，讽刺的是，你知道，
我们又在一起了，而他们却分开了。
- Yeah.
- Weird.
- 是啊。
- 好怪异。
I had a romantic moment...
在莱恩21岁的生日晚会上，
...with Rain at her
21st birthday party...
我和她一起，经历了一个
非常浪漫的时刻。
...and I could feel
the old pull coming back.
我可以感觉到那种久违的诱惑
在我体内复苏了。
The old attraction coming back.
Feelings I'd had...
你知道，就是那种久违的吸引又回来了。
我又有了从前的一些感觉…
...from my past.
It was very vivid to me.
…我感觉到了我过去的生活，
那在我看来非常的生动。
That was a-- That was a...
你知道，刚才那是个…那是个…
...a great moment.
I don't really think we should...
…伟大的时刻。
但是我真的不认为我们应该…
...follow up on it.
…由着性子下去。
What do you--? What do you mean?
噢，你什么…你什么意思？
Well, you know, I just....
If things were different--
唔，你知道，我只是……
如果情况有所不同，
If I was younger,
or if you were older...
如果我更加年轻，你知道，
或者如果你更加年长，
...or anything different,
but somehow...
或任何事情有所不同，
可是，我只是…不知怎的，
...I just feel I know how
this is gonna come out.
我就感觉到我知道
事情的结果会是怎样。
You sure?
你确定？
I am. You know, I really am.
- 我确定。你知道，我真的确定。
- 好吧。好吧。
I knew how it would end.
我知道这会怎样结束。
And I left and I walked out
into the pouring rain.
我离开她家，走出屋子，
来到瓢泼大雨里。
I just headed instinctively
back to my apartment...
你知道，一开始，我只是本能地
朝我以前的公寓方向走去，
...because I wanted to hold Judy
and kiss her...
因为…你知道，
我想抱住朱蒂并亲吻她，
...and say things to her, and then...
和她聊聊，你知道，然后…
...then I realized that, you know,
I really blew it.
…可然后我意识到，你知道，
我已经搞砸了一切。
So, what's your life like now?
那么你现在的生活如何？
I'm out of the race for now.
I don't want to get involved.
呃…你知道，目前来说我不指望什么，
我…我不想和什么人有什么瓜葛。
I don't want to hurt anyone.
I don't want to get hurt.
我不想伤害什么人，
我也不想受到伤害。我只是……
I don't mind living by
myself and working.
你知道，我只是…我不介意…
你知道，自己生活，然后工作。
It's temporary.
你知道，这只是暂时的，我是说……
I'll have the urge to get back
into the swing of things.
感情总会过去，然后我又会重新获得
踏入纷繁事务的勇气。
That seems to be how it goes.
你知道，事情看起来就该是这个样子的。
I'm writing, I'm working on a...
可是…这么说吧，你知道，我在写作，
我正在创作一部…呃…
...a new novel. Not the old
one anymore, and, um...
…一部小说，一部新的小说，
不再是老的那部了，唔……
- ...it's fine.
- Is it different?
- 你知道，还不错，绝对还行。
- 和以前有所不同吗？
My novel? Yes, it's less
confessional, more political.
我的小说？是的，这一部
少了些…自白性，多了些…政治性。
Can I go? Is this over?
我可以走了吗？这结束了没？